<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<hexagrams>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>
            The first hexagram is made up of six unbroken lines. These unbroken lines
            stand for the primal power, which is light-giving, active, strong, and of the
            spirit. The hexagram is consistently strong in character, and since it is
            without weakness, its essence is power or energy. Its image is heaven. Its
            energy is represented as unrestricted by any fixed conditions in space and is
            therefore conceived of as motion. Time is regarded as the basis of this
            motion. Thus the hexagram includes also the power of time and the power
            of persisting in time, that is, duration.
              The power represented by the hexagram is to be interpreted in a dual sense
            in terms of its action on the universe and of its action on the world of men.
            In relation to the universe, the hexagram expresses the strong, creative action
            of the Deity. In relation to the human world, it denotes the creative action of
            the holy man or sage, of the ruler or leader of men, who through his power
            awakens and develops their higher nature.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE CREATIVE works sublime success,
                Furthering through perseverance.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                According to the original meaning, the attributes [sublimity, potentiality of
                success, power to further, perseverance] are paired. When an individual
                draws this oracle, it means that success will come to him from the primal
                depths of the universe and that everything depends upon his seeking his
                happiness and that of others in one way only, that is, by perseverance in what
                is right.
                  The specific meanings of the four attributes became the subject of
                speculation at an early date. The Chinese word here rendered by "sublime"
                means literally "head," "origin," "great." This is why Confucius says in
                explaining it: "Great indeed is the generating power of the Creative; all beings
                owe their beginning to it. This power permeates all heaven." For this
                attribute inheres in the other three as well.
                  The beginning of all things lies still in the beyond in the form of ideas that
                have yet to become real. But the Creative furthermore has power to lend
                form to these archetypes of ideas. This is indicated in the word success, and
                the process is represented by an image from nature: "The clouds pass and the
                rain does its work, and all individual beings flow into their forms."
                  Applies to the human world, these attributes show the great man the way to
                notable success: "Because he sees with great clarity and cause and effects, he
                completes the six steps at the right time and mounts toward heaven on them
                at the right time, as though on sic dragons." The six steps are the six different
                positions given in the hexagram, which are represented later by the dragon
                symbol. Here it is shown that the way to success lies in apprehending and
                giving actuality to the way of the universe [Tao], which, as a law running
                through end and beginning, brings about all phenomena in time. Thus each
                step attained forthwith becomes a preparation for the next. Time is no longer
                a hindrance but the means of making actual what is potential.
                  The act of creation having found expression in the two attributes sublimity
                and success, the work of conservation is shown to be a continuous
                actualization and differentiation of form. This is expressed in the two terms
                "furthering" (literally, "creating that which accords with the nature of a
                given being") and "persevering" (literally, "correct and firm"). "The course of
                the Creative alters and shapes beings until each attains its true, specific
                nature, then it keeps them in conformity with the Great Harmony. Thus
                does it show itself to further through perseverance."
                  In relation to the human sphere, this shows how the great man brings peace
                and security to the world through his activity in creating order: "He towers
                high above the multitude of beings, and all lands are united in peace."
                  Another line of speculation goes still further in separating the words
                "sublime," "success," "furthering," "perseverance," and parallels them with
                the four cardinal virtues in humanity. To sublimity, which, as the
                fundamental principle, embraces all the other attributes, it links love. To the
                attribute success are linked the morals, which regulate and organize
                expressions of love and thereby make them successful. The attribute
                furthering is correlated with justice, which creates the conditions in which
                each receives that which accords with his being, that which is due him and
                which constitutes his happiness. The attribute perseverance is correlated
                with wisdom, which discerns the immutable laws of all that happens and can
                therefore bring about enduring conditions. These speculations, already
                broached in the commentary called Wên Yen , later formed the bridge
                connecting the philosophy of the "five stages (elements) of change," as laid
                down in the Book of History (Shu Ching) with the philosophy of the Book of
                Changes, which is based solely on the polarity of positive and negative
                principles. In the course of time this combination of the two systems of
                thought opened the way for an increasingly intricate number symbolism.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The movement of heaven is full of power.
                Thus the superior man makes himself strong and untiring.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Since there is only one heaven, the doubling of the trigram Ch'ien, of which
                heaven is the image, indicates the movement of heaven. One complete
                revolution of heaven makes a day, and the repetition of the trigram means
                that each day is followed by another. This creates the idea of time. Since it is
                the same heaven moving with untiring power, there is also created the idea
                of duration both in and beyond time, a movement that never stops nor
                slackens, just as one day follows another in an unending course. This
                duration in time is the image of the power inherent in the Creative.
                  With this image as a model, the sage learns how best to develop himself so
                that his influence may endure. He must make himself strong in every way,
                by consciously casting out all that is inferior and degrading. Thus he attains
                that tirelessness which depends upon consciously limiting the fields of his
                activity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines></lines>
    </hexagram>
</hexagrams>