<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<hexagrams>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>
            The first hexagram is made up of six unbroken lines. These unbroken lines
            stand for the primal power, which is light-giving, active, strong, and of the
            spirit. The hexagram is consistently strong in character, and since it is
            without weakness, its essence is power or energy. Its image is heaven. Its
            energy is represented as unrestricted by any fixed conditions in space and is
            therefore conceived of as motion. Time is regarded as the basis of this
            motion. Thus the hexagram includes also the power of time and the power
            of persisting in time, that is, duration.
              The power represented by the hexagram is to be interpreted in a dual sense
            in terms of its action on the universe and of its action on the world of men.
            In relation to the universe, the hexagram expresses the strong, creative action
            of the Deity. In relation to the human world, it denotes the creative action of
            the holy man or sage, of the ruler or leader of men, who through his power
            awakens and develops their higher nature.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE CREATIVE works sublime success,
                Furthering through perseverance.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                According to the original meaning, the attributes [sublimity, potentiality of
                success, power to further, perseverance] are paired. When an individual
                draws this oracle, it means that success will come to him from the primal
                depths of the universe and that everything depends upon his seeking his
                happiness and that of others in one way only, that is, by perseverance in what
                is right.
                  The specific meanings of the four attributes became the subject of
                speculation at an early date. The Chinese word here rendered by "sublime"
                means literally "head," "origin," "great." This is why Confucius says in
                explaining it: "Great indeed is the generating power of the Creative; all beings
                owe their beginning to it. This power permeates all heaven." For this
                attribute inheres in the other three as well.
                  The beginning of all things lies still in the beyond in the form of ideas that
                have yet to become real. But the Creative furthermore has power to lend
                form to these archetypes of ideas. This is indicated in the word success, and
                the process is represented by an image from nature: "The clouds pass and the
                rain does its work, and all individual beings flow into their forms."
                  Applies to the human world, these attributes show the great man the way to
                notable success: "Because he sees with great clarity and cause and effects, he
                completes the six steps at the right time and mounts toward heaven on them
                at the right time, as though on sic dragons." The six steps are the six different
                positions given in the hexagram, which are represented later by the dragon
                symbol. Here it is shown that the way to success lies in apprehending and
                giving actuality to the way of the universe [Tao], which, as a law running
                through end and beginning, brings about all phenomena in time. Thus each
                step attained forthwith becomes a preparation for the next. Time is no longer
                a hindrance but the means of making actual what is potential.
                  The act of creation having found expression in the two attributes sublimity
                and success, the work of conservation is shown to be a continuous
                actualization and differentiation of form. This is expressed in the two terms
                "furthering" (literally, "creating that which accords with the nature of a
                given being") and "persevering" (literally, "correct and firm"). "The course of
                the Creative alters and shapes beings until each attains its true, specific
                nature, then it keeps them in conformity with the Great Harmony. Thus
                does it show itself to further through perseverance."
                  In relation to the human sphere, this shows how the great man brings peace
                and security to the world through his activity in creating order: "He towers
                high above the multitude of beings, and all lands are united in peace."
                  Another line of speculation goes still further in separating the words
                "sublime," "success," "furthering," "perseverance," and parallels them with
                the four cardinal virtues in humanity. To sublimity, which, as the
                fundamental principle, embraces all the other attributes, it links love. To the
                attribute success are linked the morals, which regulate and organize
                expressions of love and thereby make them successful. The attribute
                furthering is correlated with justice, which creates the conditions in which
                each receives that which accords with his being, that which is due him and
                which constitutes his happiness. The attribute perseverance is correlated
                with wisdom, which discerns the immutable laws of all that happens and can
                therefore bring about enduring conditions. These speculations, already
                broached in the commentary called Wên Yen , later formed the bridge
                connecting the philosophy of the "five stages (elements) of change," as laid
                down in the Book of History (Shu Ching) with the philosophy of the Book of
                Changes, which is based solely on the polarity of positive and negative
                principles. In the course of time this combination of the two systems of
                thought opened the way for an increasingly intricate number symbolism.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The movement of heaven is full of power.
                Thus the superior man makes himself strong and untiring.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Since there is only one heaven, the doubling of the trigram Ch'ien, of which
                heaven is the image, indicates the movement of heaven. One complete
                revolution of heaven makes a day, and the repetition of the trigram means
                that each day is followed by another. This creates the idea of time. Since it is
                the same heaven moving with untiring power, there is also created the idea
                of duration both in and beyond time, a movement that never stops nor
                slackens, just as one day follows another in an unending course. This
                duration in time is the image of the power inherent in the Creative.
                  With this image as a model, the sage learns how best to develop himself so
                that his influence may endure. He must make himself strong in every way,
                by consciously casting out all that is inferior and degrading. Thus he attains
                that tirelessness which depends upon consciously limiting the fields of his
                activity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Hidden dragon. Do not act.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In China the dragon has a meaning altogether different from that given it in
                    the Western world. The dragon is a symbol of the electrically charged,
                    dynamic, arousing force that manifests itself in the thunderstorm. In winter
                    this energy withdraws into the earth; in the early summer it becomes active
                    again, appearing in the sky as thunder and lightning. As a result the creative
                    forces on earth begin to stir again.
                      Here this creative force is still hidden beneath the earth and therefore has
                    no effect. In terms of human affairs, this symbolizes a great man who is still
                    unrecognized. Nonetheless he remains true to himself. He does not allow
                    himself to be influenced by outward success or failure, but confident in his
                    strength, he bides his time. Hence it is wise for the man who consults the
                    oracle and draws this line to wait in the calm strength of patience. The time
                    will fulfill itself.  One need not fear least strong will should not prevail; the
                    main thing is not to expend one's powers prematurely in an attempt to obtain
                    by force something for which the time is not yet ripe.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Dragon appearing in the field.
                    It furthers one to see the great man.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the effects of the light-giving power begin to manifest themselves. In
                    terms of human affairs, this means that the great man makes his appearance
                    in his chosen field of activity. As yet he has no commanding position but is
                    still with his peers. However, what distinguishes him form the others is his
                    seriousness of purpose, his unqualified reliability, and the influence he exerts
                    on his environment without conscious effort. Such a man is destined to
                    gain great influence and to set the world in order. Therefore it is favorable to
                    see him.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    All day long the superior man is creatively active.
                    At nightfall his mind is still beset with cares.
                    Danger. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A sphere of influence opens up for the great man. His fame begins to spread.
                    The masses flock to him. His inner power is adequate to the increased outer
                    activity. There are all sorts of things to be done, and when others are at rest in
                    the evening, plans and anxieties press in upon him. But danger lurks here at
                    the place of transition from lowliness to the heights. Many a great man has
                    been ruined because the masses flocked to him and swept him into their
                    course. Ambition has destroyed his integrity. However, true greatness is not
                    impaired by temptations. He who remains in touch with the time that is
                    dawning, and with its demands is prudent enough to avoid all pitfalls, and
                    remains blameless.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Wavering flight over the depths.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A place of transition has been reached, and free choice can enter in. A
                    twofold possibility is presented to the great man: he can soar to the heights
                    and play an important part in the world, or he can withdraw into solitude
                    and develop himself. He can go the way of the hero or that of the holy sage
                    who seeks seclusion. There is no general law of his being. If the individual
                    acts consistently and is true to himself, he will find the way that is appropriate
                    for him. This way is right for him and without blame.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Flying dragon in the heavens.
                    It furthers one to see the great man.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the great man has attained the sphere of the heavenly beings. His
                    influence spreads and becomes visible throughout the whole world.
                    Everyone who sees him may count himself blessed. Confucius says about this
                    line:

                    Things that accord in tone vibrate together. Things that have affinity in their
                    inmost natures seek one another. Water flows to what is wet, fire turns to
                    what is dry. Clouds (the breath of heaven) follow the dragon, wind (the breath
                    of earth) follows the tiger. Thus the sage arises, and all creatures follow him
                    with their eyes. What is born of heaven feels related to what is above. What
                    is born of earth feels related to what is below. Each follows its kind.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Arrogant dragon will have cause to repent.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When a man seeks to climb so high that he loses touch with the rest of
                    mankind, he becomes isolated, and this necessarily leads to failure. This line
                    warns against titanic aspirations that exceed one's power. A precipitous fall
                    would follow.
                </meaning>
            </six>
            <all>
                <text>
                    There appears a flight of dragons without heads.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When all the lines are nines, it means that the whole hexagram is in motion
                    and changes into the hexagram K'un, THE RECEPTIVE, whose character is
                    devotion. The strength of the Creative and the mildness of the Receptive
                    unite. Strength is indicated by the flight of dragons, mildness by the fact that
                    their heads are hidden. This means that mildness in action joined to strength
                    of decision brings good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </all>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Receptive" number="2">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of broken lines only. The broken lines represents
            the dark, yielding, receptive primal power of yin. The attribute of the
            hexagram is devotion; its image is the earth.  It is the perfect complement of
            THE CREATIVE— the complement, not the opposite, for the Receptive does
            not combat the Creative but completes it . It represents nature in contrast to
            spirit, earth in contrast to heaven, space as against time, the female-maternal
            as against the male-paternal. However, as applied to human affairs, the
            principle of this complementary relationship is found not only in the relation
            between man and woman, but also in that between prince and minister and
            between father and son. Indeed, even in the individual this duality appears
            in the coexistence of the spiritual world and the world of the senses.
              But strictly speaking there is no real dualism here, because there is a clearly
            defined hierarchic relationship between the two principles. In itself of course
            the Receptive is just as important as the Creative, but the attribute of
            devotion defines the place occupied by this primal power in relation to the
            Creative. For the Receptive must be activated and led by the Creative; then it
            is productive of good. Only when it abandons this position and tries to stand
            as an equal side by side with the Creative, does it become evil.  The result
            then is opposition to and struggle against the Creative, which is productive of
            evil to both.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE RECEPTIVE brings about sublime success,
                Furthering through the perseverance of a mare.
                If the superior man undertakes something and tries to lead,
                He goes astray;
                But if he follows, he finds guidance.
                It is favorable to find friends in the west and south,
                To forego friends in the east and north.
                Quiet perseverance brings good fortune.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The four fundamental aspects of the Creative— "sublime success, furthering
                through perseverance"— are also attributed to the Receptive.  Here, however,
                the perseverance is more closely defined: it is that of a mare. The Receptive
                connotes spatial reality in contrast to the spiritual potentiality of the Creative.
                The potential becomes real and the spiritual becomes spatial through a
                specifically qualifying definition. Thus the qualification, "of a mare," is here
                added to the idea of perseverance. The horse belongs to earth just as the
                dragon belongs to heaven. Its tireless roaming over the plains is taken as a
                symbol of the vast expanse of the earth. This is the symbol chosen because
                the mare combines the strength and swiftness of the horse with the
                gentleness and devotion of the cow.
                  Only because nature in its myriad forms corresponds with the myriad
                impulses of the Creative can it make these impulses real. Nature's richness
                lies in its power to nourish all living things; its greatness lies in its power to
                give then beauty and splendor. Thus it prospers all that lives. IT is the
                Creative that begets things, but they are brought to birth by the Receptive.
                Applied to human affairs, therefore, what the hexagram indicated is action in
                conformity with the situation. The person in questions not in an
                independent position, but is acting as an assistant. This means that he must
                achieve something. It is not his task to try to lead— that would only make him
                lose the way-but to let himself be led. If he knows how to meet fate with an
                attitude of acceptance, he is sure to find the right guidance. The superior man
                lets himself be guided; he does not go ahead blindly, but learns from the
                situation what is demanded of him and then follows this intimation from
                fate.
                  Since there is something to be accomplished, we need friends and helpers in
                the hour of toil and effort, once the ideas to be realized are firmly set. The
                time of toil and effort is indicated by the west and south, for west and south
                symbolize the place where the Receptive works for the Creative, as nature
                does in summer and autumn. If in that situation one does not mobilize all
                one's powers, the work to be accomplished will not be done. Hence to find
                friends there means to find guidance. But in addition to the time of toil and
                effort, there is also a time of planning, and for this we need this solitude. The
                east symbolized the place where a man receives orders from his master, and
                the north the place where he reports on what he has done. At that time he
                must be alone and objective. In this sacred hour he must do without
                companions. So that the purity of the moment may not be spoiled by fictional
                hates and favoritism.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The earth's condition is receptive devotion.
                Thus the superior man who has breadth of character
                Carries the outer world.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Just as there is only one heaven, so too there is only one earth. In the
                hexagram of heaven the doubling of the trigram implies duration in time,
                but in the hexagram of earth the doubling connotes the solidity and extension
                in space by virtue of which the earth is able to carry and preserve all things
                that live and move upon it. The earth in its devotion carries all things, good
                and evil,, without exception. In the same way the superior man gives to his
                character breadth, purity, and sustaining power, so that he is able both to
                support and to bear with people and things.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    When there is hoarfrost underfoot,
                    Solid ice is not far off.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Just as the light-giving power represents life, so the dark power, the shadowy,
                    represents death. When the first hoarfrost comes in the autumn, the power
                    of darkness and cold is just at its beginning. After these first warnings, signs
                    of death will gradually multiply, until, in obedience to immutable laws, stark
                    winter with its ice is here.
                      In life it is the same. After certain scarcely noticeable signs of decay have
                    appeared, they go on increasing until final dissolution comes. But in life
                    precautions can be taken by heeding the first signs of decay and checking them
                    in time.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Straight, square, great.
                    Without purpose,
                    Yet nothing remains unfurthered.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The symbol of heaven is the circle, and that of earth is the square. Thus
                    squareness is a primary quality of the earth. On the other hand, movement
                    in a straight line, as well as magnitude, is a primary quality of the Creative.
                    But all square things have their origin in a straight line and into turn form
                    solid bodies. In mathematics, when we discriminate between lines, planes
                    and solids, we find that rectangular planes result from straight lines, and
                    cubic magnitudes from rectangular planes. The Receptive accommodates
                    itself to the qualities of the Creative and makes them its own. Thus a square
                    develops out of a straight line and a cube out of a square. This is compliance
                    with the laws of the Creative; nothing is taken away, nothing added.
                    Therefore the Receptive has no need of a special purpose of its own, nor of
                    any effort' yet everything turns out as it should.
                      Nature creates all beings without erring: this is its foursquareness. It
                    tolerates all creatures equally: this is its greatness. Therefore it attains what is
                    right for all without artifice or special intentions. Man achieves the height of
                    wisdom when all that he does is as self-evident as what nature does.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Hidden lines.
                    One is able to remain persevering.
                    If by chance you are in the service of a king,
                    Seek not works, but bring to completion.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a man is free of vanity he is able to conceal his abilities and keep them from
                    attracting attention too soon; thus he can mature undisturbed.  If conditions
                    demand it, he can also enter public life, but that too he does with restraint.
                    The wise man gladly leaves fame to others. He does not seek to have credited
                    to himself things that stand accomplished, but hopes to release active forces;
                    that is, he completes his works in such a manner that they may bear fruit for
                    the future.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    A tied-up sack. No blame, no praise.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The dark element opens when it moves and closes when at rest. The strictest
                    reticence is indicated here. The time is dangerous , because any degree of
                    prominence leads either to the enmity of irresistible antagonists if one
                    challenges them or to misconceived recognition if one is complaisant.
                    Therefore a man ought to maintain reserve, be it in solitude or in the turmoil
                    of the world, for there too he can hide himself so well that no one knows
                    him.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    A yellow lower garment brings supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Yellow is the color of the earth and of the middle; it is the symbol of that
                    which is reliable and genuine. The lower garment is inconspicuously
                    decorated— the symbol of aristocratic reserve. When anyone is called upon to
                    work in a prominent but not independent position, true success depends on
                    the utmost discretion. A man's genuineness and refinement should not
                    reveal themselves directly; they should express themselves only indirectly as
                    an effect from within.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Dragons fight in the meadow.
                    Their blood is black and yellow.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the top place the dark element should yield to the light. If it attempts to
                    maintain a position to which it is not entitled and to rule instead of serving,
                    it draws down upon itself the anger of the strong. A struggle ensues in which
                    it is overthrown, with injury, however, to both sides. The dragon, symbol of
                    heaven, comes to fight the false dragon that symbolized the inflation of the
                    earth principle. Midnight blue is the color of heaven; yellow is the color of
                    earth. Therefore, when black and yellow blood flow, it is a sign that in this
                    unnatural contest both primal powers suffer injury.
                </meaning>
            </six>
            <all>
                <text>
                    When all the lines are sixes, it means:
                    Lasting perseverance furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When nothing but sixes appears, the hexagram of THE RECEPTIVE changes
                    into the hexagram of THE CREATIVE. By holding fast to what is right, it
                    gains the power of enduring. There is indeed no advance, but neither is there
                    retrogression.
                </meaning>
            </all>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Difficulty at the Beginning" number="3">
        <description>
                The name of the hexagram, Chun, really connotes a blade of grass pushing
                against an obstacle as it sprouts out of the earth— hence the meaning,
                "difficulty at the beginning." The hexagram indicates the way in which
                heaven and earth bring forth individual beings. It is their first meeting,
                which is beset with difficulties. The lower trigram Chên is the Arousing; its
                motion is upward and its image is thunder. The upper trigram K'an stands
                for the Abysmal, the dangerous. Its motion is downward and its image is
                rain. The situation points to teeming, chaotic profusion; thunder and rain fill
                the air. But the chaos clears up. While the Abysmal sinks, the upward
                movement eventually passes beyond the danger. A thunderstorm brings
                release from tension, and all things breathe freely again.
            </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                DIFFICULTY AT THE BEGINNING works supreme success,
                Furthering through perseverance.
                Nothing should be undertaken.
                It furthers one to appoint helpers.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Times of growth are beset with difficulties. They resemble a first birth. But
                these difficulties arise from the very profusion of all that is struggling to
                attain form . Everything is in motion: therefore if one perseveres there is a
                prospect of great success, in spite of the existing danger. When it is a man's
                fate to undertake such new beginnings, everything is still unformed, dark.
                Hence he must hold back, because any premature move might bring disaster.
                Likewise, it is very important not to remain alone; in order to overcome the
                chaos he needs helpers. This is not to say, however, that he himself should
                look on passively at what is happening. He must lend his hand and
                participate with inspiration and guidance.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Clouds and thunder:
                The image of DIFFICULTY AT THE BEGINNING.
                Thus the superior man
                Brings order out of confusion.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Clouds and thunder are represented by definite decorative lines; this means
                that in the chaos of difficulty at the beginning, order is already implicit. So
                too the superior man has to arrange and organize the inchoate profusion of
                such times of beginning, just as one sorts out silk threads from a knotted
                tangle and binds them into skeins. In order to find one's place in the infinity
                of being, one must be able both to separate and to unite.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Hesitation and hindrance.
                    It furthers one to remain persevering.
                    It furthers one to appoint helpers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a person encounters a hindrance at the beginning of an enterprise, he must
                    not try to force advance but must pause and take thought. However, nothing
                    should put him off his course; he must persevere and constantly keep the
                    goal in sight. It is important to seek out the right assistants, but he can find
                    them only if he avoids arrogance and associated with his fellows in a spirit of
                    humility. Only then will he attract those with whose help he can combat the
                    difficulties.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Difficulties pile up.
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    He is not a robber;
                    He wants to woo when the time comes.
                    The maiden is chaste,
                    She does not pledge herself.
                    Ten years— then she pledges herself.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We find ourselves beset by difficulties and hindrances. Suddenly there is a
                    turn of affairs, as if someone were coming up with a horse and wagon and
                    unhitching them. This event comes so unexpectedly that we assume the
                    newcomer to be a robber. Gradually it becomes clear that he has no evil
                    intentions but seeks to be friendly and to offer help. But this offer is not to be
                    accepted, because it does not come from the right quarter. We must wait until
                    the time is fulfilled; ten years is a fulfilled cycle of time. Then normal
                    conditions return of themselves, and we can join forces with the friend
                    intended for us.
                      Using the image of a betrothed girl who remains true to her lover in face of
                    grave conflicts, the hexagram gives counsel for a special situation. When in
                    times of difficulty a hindrance is encountered and unexpected relief is offered
                    from a source unrelated to us, we must be careful and not take upon
                    ourselves any obligations entailed by such help; otherwise our freedom of
                    decision is impaired. If we bide our time, things will quiet down again, and
                    we shall attain what we have hoped for.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Whoever hunts deer without the forester
                    Only loses his way in the forest.
                    The superior man understands the signs of the time
                    And prefers to desist.
                    To go on brings humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a man tries to hunt in a strange forest and has no guide, he loses his way.
                    When he finds himself in difficulties he must not try to steal out of them
                    unthinkingly and without guidance. Fate cannot be duped; premature effort,
                    without the necessary guidance, ends in failure and disgrace.  Therefore the
                    superior man, discerning the seeds of coming events, prefers to renounce a
                    wish rather than to provoke failure and humiliation by trying to force its
                    fulfillment.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    Strive for union.
                    To go brings good fortune.
                    Everything acts to further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We are in a situation in which it is our duty to act, but we lack sufficient
                    power. However, an opportunity to make connections offers itself. It must be
                    seized. Neither false pride nor false reserve should deter us. Bringing oneself
                    to take the first step, even when it involves a certain degree of self-
                    abnegation, is a sign of inner clarity. To accept help in a difficult situation is
                    not a disgrace. If the right helper is found, all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Difficulties in blessing.
                    A little perseverance brings good fortune.
                    Great perseverance brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An individual is in a position in which he cannot so express his good
                    intentions that they will actually take shape and be understood. Other people
                    interpose and distort everything he does. He should then be cautious and
                    proceed step by step. He must not try to force the consummation of a great
                    undertaking, because success is possible only when general confidence already
                    prevails. It is only through faithful and conscientious work, unobtrusively
                    carried on, that the situation gradually clears up and the hindrance
                    disappears.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    Bloody tears flow.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The difficulties at the beginning are too great for some persons. They get
                    stuck and never find their way out; they fold their hands and give up the
                    struggle. Such resignation is the saddest of all things. Therefore Confucius
                    says of this line: "Bloody tears flow: one should not persist in this."
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Youthful Folly" number="4">
        <description>
            In this hexagram we are reminded of youth and folly in two different ways.
            The image of the upper trigram, Kên, is the mountain, that of the lower,
            K'an, is water; the spring rising at the foot of the mountain is the image of
            inexperienced youth. Keeping still is the attribute of the upper trigram; that of
            the lower is the abyss, danger. Stopping in perplexity on the brink of a
            dangerous abyss is a symbol of the folly of youth. However, the two trigrams
            also show the way of overcoming the follies of youth. Water is something
            that of necessity flows on. When the spring gushes forth, it does not know at
            first where it will go. But its steady flow fills up the deep place blocking its
            progress, and success is attained.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                YOUTHFUL FOLLY has success.
                It is not I who seek the young fool;
                The young fool seeks me.
                At the first oracle I inform him.
                If he asks two or three times, it is importunity.
                If he importunes, I give him no information.
                Perseverance furthers.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In the time of youth, folly is not an evil. One may succeed in spite of it,
                provided one finds an experienced teacher and has the right attitude toward
                him. This means, first of all, that the youth himself must be conscious of his
                lack of experience and must seek out the teacher. Without this modesty and
                this interest there is no guarantee that he has the necessary receptivity, which
                should express itself in respectful acceptance of the teacher. This is the reason
                why the teacher must wait to be sought out instead of offering himself. Only
                thus can the instruction take place at the right time and in the right way.
                  A teacher's answer to the question of a pupil ought to be clear and definite
                like that expected from an oracle; thereupon it ought to be accepted as a key
                for resolution of doubts and a basis for decision. If mistrustful or
                unintelligent questioning is kept up, it serves only to annoy the teacher. He
                does well to ignore it in silence, just as the oracle gives one answer only and
                refuses to be tempted by questions implying doubt.
                  Given addition a perseverance that never slackens until the points are
                mastered one by one, real success is sure to follow. Thus the hexagram
                counsels the teacher as well as the pupil.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                A spring wells up at the foot of the mountain:
                The image of YOUTH.
                Thus the superior man fosters his character
                By thoroughness in all that he does.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                A spring succeeds in flowing on and escapes stagnation by filling up all the
                hollow places in its path. In the same way character is developed by
                thoroughness that skips nothing but, like water, gradually and steadily fills up
                all gaps and so flows onward.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    To make a fool develop
                    It furthers one to apply discipline.
                    The fetters should be removed.
                    To go on in this way bring humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Law is the beginning of education. Youth in its inexperience is inclined at first
                    to take everything carelessly and playfully.  It must be shown the seriousness
                    of life. A certain measure of taking oneself in hand, brought about by strict
                    discipline, is a good thing. He who plays with life never amounts to
                    anything. However, discipline should not degenerate into drill. Continuous
                    drill has a humiliating effect and cripples a man's powers.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    To bear with fools in kindliness brings good fortune.
                    To know how to take women
                    Brings good fortune.
                    The son is capable of taking charge of the household.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    These lines picture a man who has no external power, but who has enough
                    strength of mind to bear his burden of responsibility. He has the inner
                    superiority and that enable him to tolerate with kindliness the shortcomings
                    of human folly. The same attitude is owed to women as the weaker sex. One
                    must understand them and give them recognition in a spirit of chivalrous
                    consideration. Only this combination of inner strength with outer reserve
                    enables one to take on the responsibility of directing a larger social body with
                    real success.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Take not a maiden who. When she sees a man of bronze,
                    Loses possession of herself.
                    Nothing furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A weak, inexperienced man, struggling to rise, easily loses his own
                    individuality when he slavishly imitates a strong personality of higher
                    station. He is like a girl throwing herself away when she meets a strong man.
                    Such a servile approach should not be encouraged, because it is bad both for
                    the youth and the teacher. A girl owes it to her dignity to wait until she is
                    wooed. In both cases it is undignified to offer oneself, and no good comes of
                    accepting such an offer.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Entangled folly bring humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    For youthful folly it is the most hopeless thing to entangle itself in empty
                    imaginings. The more obstinately it clings to such unreal fantasies, the more
                    certainly will humiliation overtake it.
                     Often the teacher, when confronted with such entangled folly, has no other
                    course but to leave the fool to himself for a time, not sparing him the
                    humiliation that results. This is frequently the only means of rescue.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Childlike folly brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An inexperienced person who seeks instruction in a childlike and
                    unassuming way is on the right path, for the man devoid of arrogance who
                    subordinated himself to his teacher will certainly be helped.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    In punishing folly
                    It does not further one
                    To commit transgressions.
                    The only thing that furthers
                    Is to prevent transgressions.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Sometimes an incorrigible fool must be punished. He who will not heed will
                    be made to feel. This punishment is quite different from a preliminary
                    shaking up. But the penalty should not be imposed in anger; it must be
                    restricted to an objective guarding against unjustified excesses. Punishment
                    is never an end in itself but serves merely to restore order.
                      This applies not only in regard to education but also in regard to the
                    measures taken by a government against a populace guilty of transgressions.
                    Governmental interference should always be merely preventive and should
                    have as its sole aim the establishment of public security and peace.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Waiting (Nourishment)" number="5">
        <description>
            All beings have need of nourishment from above. But the gift of food comes
            in its own time, and for this one must wait. This hexagram shows the clouds
            in the heavens, giving rain to refresh all that grows and to provide mankind
            with food and drink. The rain will come in its own time. We cannot make it
            come; we have to wait for it. The idea of waiting is further suggested by the
            attributes of the two trigrams— strength within, danger in from. Strength in
            the face of danger does not plunge ahead but bides its time, whereas weakness
            in the face of danger grows agitated and has not the patience to wait.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                WAITING. If you are sincere,
                You have light and success.
                Perseverance brings good fortune.
                It furthers one to cross the great water.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Waiting is not mere empty hoping. It has the inner certainty of reaching the
                goal. Such certainty alone gives that light which leads to success. This leads
                to the perseverance that brings good fortune and bestows power to cross the
                great water. One is faced with a danger that has to be overcome. Weakness
                and impatience can do nothing. Only a strong man can stand up to his fate,
                for his inner security enables him to endure to the end. This strength shows
                itself in uncompromising truthfulness [with himself]. It is only when we
                have the courage to face things exactly as they are, without any sort of self-
                deception or illusion, that a light will develop out of events, by which the
                path to success may be recognized. This recognition must be followed by
                resolute and persevering action. For only the man who goes to meet his fate
                resolutely is equipped to deal with it adequately. Then he will be able to cross
                the great water— that is to say, he will be capable of making the necessary
                decision and of surmounting the danger.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Clouds rise up to heaven:
                The image of WAITING.
                Thus the superior man eats and drinks,
                Is joyous and of good cheer.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When clouds rise in the sky, it is a sign that it will rain. There is nothing to
                do but to wait until after the rain falls. It is the same in life when destiny is at
                work. We should not worry and seek to shape the future by interfering in
                things before the time is ripe. We should quietly fortify the body with food
                and drink and the mind with gladness and good cheer. Fate comes when it
                will, and thus we are ready.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Waiting in the meadow.
                    IT furthers one to abide in what endures.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The danger is not yet close. One is still waiting on the open plain.
                    Conditions are still simple, yet there is a feeling of something impending.
                    One must continue to lead a regular life as long as possible. Only in this way
                    does one guard against a premature waste of strength, keep free of blame and
                    error that would become a source of weakness later on.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Waiting on the sand.
                    There is some gossip.
                    The end brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The danger gradually comes closer. Sand is near the bank of the river, and
                    the water means danger. Disagreements crop up. General unrest can easily
                    develop in such times, and we lay the blame on one another. He who stays
                    calm will succeed in making things go well in the end. Slander will be
                    silenced if we do not gratify it with injured retorts.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Waiting in the mud
                    Brings about the arrival of the enemy.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Mud is no place for waiting, since it is already being washed by the water of
                    the stream. Instead of having gathered strength to cross the stream at one try,
                    one has made a premature start that has got him no farther than the muddy
                    bank. Such an unfavorable position invites enemies from without, who
                    naturally take advantage of it. Caution and a sense of the seriousness of the
                    situation are all that can keep one from injury.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Waiting in blood.
                    Get out of the pit.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The situation is extremely dangerous. IT is of utmost gravity now— a matter
                    of life and death. Bloodshed seems imminent. There is no going forward or
                    backward; we are cut off as if in a pit. Now we must simply stand fast and let
                    fate take its course. This composure, which keeps us from aggravating the
                    trouble by anything we might do, is the only way of getting out of the
                    dangerous pit.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Waiting at meat and drink.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Even in the midst of danger there come intervals of peace when things go
                    relatively well. If we possess enough inner strength, we shall take advantage
                    of these intervals to fortify ourselves for renewed struggle. We must know
                    how to enjoy the moment without being deflected from the goal, for
                    perseverance is needed to remain victorious.
                      This is true in public life as well; it is not possible to achieve everything all
                    at once. The height of wisdom is to allow people enough recreation to
                    quicken pleasure in their work until the task is completed. Herein lies the
                    secret of the whole hexagram. It differs from Chin OBSTRUCTION (39), in
                    the fact that in this instance, while waiting, we are sure of our cause and
                    therefore do not lose the serenity born of inner cheerfulness.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    One falls into the pit.
                    Three uninvited guests arrive.
                    Honor them, and in the end there will be good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The waiting is over; the danger can no longer be averted.  One falls into the
                    pit and must yield to the inevitable. Everything seems to have been in vain.
                    But precisely in this extremity things take an unforeseen turn.  Without a
                    move on one's own part, there is outside intervention. At first one cannot be
                    sure of its meaning: is it rescue or is it destruction? A person in this
                    situation must keep his mind alert and not withdraw into himself with a
                    sulky gesture of refusal, but must greet the new turn with respect. Thus he
                    ultimately escapes the danger, and all goes well. Even happy turns of fortune
                    often come in a form that at first seems strange to us.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Conflict" number="6">
        <description>
            The upper trigram, whose image is heaven, has an upward movement; the
            lower trigram, water, in accordance with its nature tends downward. Thus the
            two halves move away from each other, giving rise to the idea of conflict.
              The attribute of the Creative is strength, that of the Abysmal is danger, guile.
            Where cunning has force before it, there is conflict.
              A third indication of conflict, in terms of character, is presented by the
            combination of deep cunning within and fixed determination outwardly. A
            person of this character will certainly be quarrelsome.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                CONFLICT. You are sincere
                And are being obstructed.
                A cautious halt halfway brings good fortune.
                Going through to the end brings misfortune.
                It furthers one to see the great man.
                It does not further one to cross the great water.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Conflict develops when one feels himself to be in the right and runs into
                opposition. If one is not convinced of being in the right, opposition leads to
                craftiness or high-handed encroachment but not to open conflict.
                  If a man is entangled in a conflict, his only salvation lies in being so clear-
                headed and inwardly strong that he is always ready to come to terms by
                meeting the opponent halfway. To carry one the conflict to the bitter end has
                evil effects even when one is the right, because the enmity is then
                perpetuated. It is important to see the great man, that is, an impartial man
                whose authority is great enough to terminate the conflict amicably or assure a
                just decision. In times of strife, crossing the great water is to be avoided, that
                is, dangerous enterprises are not to be begun, because in order to be successful
                they require concerted unity of focus. Conflict within weakens the power to
                conquer danger without.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven and water go their opposite ways:
                The image of CONFLICT.
                Thus in all his transactions the superior man
                Carefully considers the beginning.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The image indicates that the causes of conflict are latent in the opposing
                tendencies of the two trig rams. Once these opposing tendencies appear,
                conflict is inevitable. To avoid it, therefore, everything must be taken
                carefully into consideration in the very beginning. If rights and duties are
                exactly defined, or if, in a group, the spiritual trends of the individuals
                harmonize, the cause of conflict is removed in advance.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    If one does not perpetuate the affair,
                    There is a little gossip.
                    In the end, good fortune comes.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    While a conflict is in the incipient stage, the best thing To do is to drop the
                    issue. Especially when the adversary is stronger, it is not advisable to risk
                    pushing the conflict to a decision. It may come to a slight dispute, but in the
                    end all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    One cannot engage in conflict;
                    One returns home, gives way.
                    The people of his town,
                    Three hundred households,
                    Remain free of guilt.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In a struggle with an enemy of superior strength, retreat is no disgrace.
                    Timely withdrawal prevents bad consequences. If, out of a false sense of
                    honor, a man allowed himself to be tempted into an unequal conflict, he
                    would be drawing down disaster upon himself. In such a case a wise and
                    conciliatory attitude benefits the whole community, which will then not be
                    drawn into the conflict.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    To nourish oneself on ancient virtue induces perseverance.
                    Danger. In the end, good fortune comes.
                    If by chance you are in the service of a king,
                    Seek not works.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This is a warning of the danger that goes with an expansive disposition. Only
                    that which has been honestly acquired through merit remains a permanent
                    possession. It can happen that such a possession may be contested, but since it
                    is really one's own, one cannot be robbed of it. Whatever a man possesses
                    through the strength of his own nature cannot be lost. If one enters the
                    service of a superior, one can avoid conflict only by not seeking works for the
                    sake of prestige. It is enough if the work is done: let the honor go to the
                    other.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    One cannot engage in conflict.
                    One turns back and submits to fate,
                    Changes one's attitude,
                    And finds peace in perseverance.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to a person whose inner attitude at first lacks peace. He does not
                    feel content with his situation and would like to improve it through conflict.
                    In contrast tot the situation of the nine in the second place, he is dealing with
                    a weaker opponent and might therefore succeed. But he cannot carry on the
                    fight, because, since right is not on his side, he cannot justify the conflict to
                    his conscience. Therefore he turns back and accepts his fate. He changes his
                    mind and finds lasting peace in being at one with eternal law. This brings
                    good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    To contend before him
                    Brings supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to an arbiter in a conflict who is powerful and just, and strong
                    enough to lend weight to the right side. A dispute can be turned over to him
                    with confidence. If one is in the right, one attains great good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Even if by chance a leather belt is bestowed on one,'
                    By the end of a morning
                    It will have been snatched away three times.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here we have someone who has carried a conflict to the bitter end and has
                    triumphed. He is granted a decoration, but his happiness does not last.  He is
                    attacked again and again, and the result is conflict without end.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Army" number="7">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of the trigrams K'an, water, and K'un, earth, and
            thus it symbolizes the ground water stored up in the earth. In the same way
            military strength is stored up in the mass of the people— invisible in times of
            peace but always ready for use as a source of power. The attributes of the two
            trig rams are danger inside and obedience must prevail outside.
              Of the individual lines, the one that controls the hexagram is the strong
            nine in the second place, to which the other lines, all yielding, are
            subordinate. This line indicates a commander, because it stands in the
            middle of one of the two trigrams. But since it is in the lower rather than the
            upper trigram, it represents not the ruler but the efficient general, who
            maintains obedience in the army by his authority.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE ARMY. The army needs perseverance
                And a strong man.
                Good fortune without blame.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                An army is a mass that needs organization in order to become a fighting force.
                Without strict discipline nothing can be accomplished, but this discipline
                must not be achieved by force. It requires a strong man who captures the
                hearts of the people and awakens their enthusiasm. In order that he may
                develop his abilities he needs the complete confidence of his ruler, who must
                entrust him with full responsibility as long as the war lasts. But war is always
                a dangerous thing and brings with it destruction and devastation. Therefore
                it should not be resorted to rashly but, like a poisonous drug, should be used
                as a last recourse.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                In the middle of the earth is water:
                The image of THE ARMY.
                Thus the superior man increases his masses
                By generosity toward the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Ground water is invisibly present within the earth. In the same way the
                military power of a people is invisibly present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes a soldier; when the war ends, he goes back
                to his plow. He who is generous toward the people wins their love, and a
                people living under a mild rule becomes strong and powerful. Only a people
                economically strong can be important in military power. Such power must
                therefore be cultivated by improving the economic condition of the people
                and by humane government. Only when there is this invisible bond between
                government and people, so that the people are sheltered by their
                government as ground water is sheltered by the earth, is it possible to wage a
                victorious war.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    An army must set forth in proper order.
                    If the order is not good, misfortune threatens.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    At the beginning of a military enterprise, order is imperative. A just and
                    valid cause must exist, and the obedience and coordination of the troops must
                    be well organized, otherwise the result is inevitably failure.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    In the midst of the army.
                    Good fortune. No blame.
                    The king bestows a triple decoration.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The leader should be in the midst of his army, in touch with it, sharing good
                    and bad with the masses he leads. This alone makes him equal to the heavy
                    demands made upon him. He needs also the recognition of the ruler. The
                    decorations he receives are justified, because there is no question of personal
                    preferment here: the whole army, whose center he is, is honored in his
                    person.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Perchance the army carries corpses in the wagon.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here we have a choice of two explanations. One points to defeat because
                    someone other than the chosen leader interferes with the command; the
                    other is similar in its general meaning, but the expression, "carries corpses in
                    the wagon," is interpreted differently. At burials and at sacrifices to the dead it
                    was customary in China for the deceased to whom the sacrifice was made to
                    be represented by a boy of the family, who sat in the dead man's place and was
                    honored as his representative. On the basis of this custom the text is
                    interpreted as meaning that a "corpse boy" is sitting in the wagon, or, in
                    other words, that authority is not being exercised by the proper leaders but has
                    been usurped by others. Perhaps the whole difficulty clears up if it is inferred
                    that there has been an error in copying. The character fan, meaning "all," may
                    have been misread as shih, which means "corpse." Allowing for this error,
                    the meaning would be that if the multitude assumes leadership of the army
                    (rides in the wagon), misfortune will ensue.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The army retreats. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the face of a superior enemy, with whom it would be hopeless to engage in
                    battle, an orderly retreat is the only correct procedure, because it will save the
                    army from defeat and disintegration. It is by no means a sign of courage or
                    strength to insist upon engaging in a hopeless struggle regardless of
                    circumstances.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    There is game in the field.
                    It furthers one to catch it.
                    Without blame.
                    Let the eldest lead the army.
                    The younger transports corpses;
                    Then perseverance brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Game is in the field— it has left its usual haunts in the forest and is
                    devastating the fields. This points to an enemy invasion. Energetic combat
                    and punishment are here thoroughly justified, but they must not degenerate
                    into a wild melee in which everyone fends for himself. Despite the greatest
                    degree of perseverance and bravery, this would lead to misfortune. The army
                    must be directed by an experienced leader. It is a matter of waging war, not of
                    permitting the mob to slaughter all who fall into their hands; if they do,
                    defeat will be the result, and despite all perseverance there is danger of
                    misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The great prince issues commands,
                    Founds states, vests families with fiefs.
                    Inferior people should not be employed.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The war has ended successfully, victory is won, and the king divided estates
                    and fiefs among his faithful vassals. But it is important that inferior people
                    should not come into power. If they have helped, let them be paid off with
                    money, but they should not be awarded lands or the privileges of rulers, lest
                    power be abused.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
</hexagrams>