<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<hexagrams>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>
            The first hexagram is made up of six unbroken lines. These unbroken lines
            stand for the primal power, which is light-giving, active, strong, and of the
            spirit. The hexagram is consistently strong in character, and since it is
            without weakness, its essence is power or energy. Its image is heaven. Its
            energy is represented as unrestricted by any fixed conditions in space and is
            therefore conceived of as motion. Time is regarded as the basis of this
            motion. Thus the hexagram includes also the power of time and the power
            of persisting in time, that is, duration.
              The power represented by the hexagram is to be interpreted in a dual sense
            in terms of its action on the universe and of its action on the world of men.
            In relation to the universe, the hexagram expresses the strong, creative action
            of the Deity. In relation to the human world, it denotes the creative action of
            the holy man or sage, of the ruler or leader of men, who through his power
            awakens and develops their higher nature.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE CREATIVE works sublime success,
                Furthering through perseverance.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                According to the original meaning, the attributes [sublimity, potentiality of
                success, power to further, perseverance] are paired. When an individual
                draws this oracle, it means that success will come to him from the primal
                depths of the universe and that everything depends upon his seeking his
                happiness and that of others in one way only, that is, by perseverance in what
                is right.
                  The specific meanings of the four attributes became the subject of
                speculation at an early date. The Chinese word here rendered by "sublime"
                means literally "head," "origin," "great." This is why Confucius says in
                explaining it: "Great indeed is the generating power of the Creative; all beings
                owe their beginning to it. This power permeates all heaven." For this
                attribute inheres in the other three as well.
                  The beginning of all things lies still in the beyond in the form of ideas that
                have yet to become real. But the Creative furthermore has power to lend
                form to these archetypes of ideas. This is indicated in the word success, and
                the process is represented by an image from nature: "The clouds pass and the
                rain does its work, and all individual beings flow into their forms."
                  Applies to the human world, these attributes show the great man the way to
                notable success: "Because he sees with great clarity and cause and effects, he
                completes the six steps at the right time and mounts toward heaven on them
                at the right time, as though on sic dragons." The six steps are the six different
                positions given in the hexagram, which are represented later by the dragon
                symbol. Here it is shown that the way to success lies in apprehending and
                giving actuality to the way of the universe [Tao], which, as a law running
                through end and beginning, brings about all phenomena in time. Thus each
                step attained forthwith becomes a preparation for the next. Time is no longer
                a hindrance but the means of making actual what is potential.
                  The act of creation having found expression in the two attributes sublimity
                and success, the work of conservation is shown to be a continuous
                actualization and differentiation of form. This is expressed in the two terms
                "furthering" (literally, "creating that which accords with the nature of a
                given being") and "persevering" (literally, "correct and firm"). "The course of
                the Creative alters and shapes beings until each attains its true, specific
                nature, then it keeps them in conformity with the Great Harmony. Thus
                does it show itself to further through perseverance."
                  In relation to the human sphere, this shows how the great man brings peace
                and security to the world through his activity in creating order: "He towers
                high above the multitude of beings, and all lands are united in peace."
                  Another line of speculation goes still further in separating the words
                "sublime," "success," "furthering," "perseverance," and parallels them with
                the four cardinal virtues in humanity. To sublimity, which, as the
                fundamental principle, embraces all the other attributes, it links love. To the
                attribute success are linked the morals, which regulate and organize
                expressions of love and thereby make them successful. The attribute
                furthering is correlated with justice, which creates the conditions in which
                each receives that which accords with his being, that which is due him and
                which constitutes his happiness. The attribute perseverance is correlated
                with wisdom, which discerns the immutable laws of all that happens and can
                therefore bring about enduring conditions. These speculations, already
                broached in the commentary called Wên Yen , later formed the bridge
                connecting the philosophy of the "five stages (elements) of change," as laid
                down in the Book of History (Shu Ching) with the philosophy of the Book of
                Changes, which is based solely on the polarity of positive and negative
                principles. In the course of time this combination of the two systems of
                thought opened the way for an increasingly intricate number symbolism.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The movement of heaven is full of power.
                Thus the superior man makes himself strong and untiring.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Since there is only one heaven, the doubling of the trigram Ch'ien, of which
                heaven is the image, indicates the movement of heaven. One complete
                revolution of heaven makes a day, and the repetition of the trigram means
                that each day is followed by another. This creates the idea of time. Since it is
                the same heaven moving with untiring power, there is also created the idea
                of duration both in and beyond time, a movement that never stops nor
                slackens, just as one day follows another in an unending course. This
                duration in time is the image of the power inherent in the Creative.
                  With this image as a model, the sage learns how best to develop himself so
                that his influence may endure. He must make himself strong in every way,
                by consciously casting out all that is inferior and degrading. Thus he attains
                that tirelessness which depends upon consciously limiting the fields of his
                activity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Hidden dragon. Do not act.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In China the dragon has a meaning altogether different from that given it in
                    the Western world. The dragon is a symbol of the electrically charged,
                    dynamic, arousing force that manifests itself in the thunderstorm. In winter
                    this energy withdraws into the earth; in the early summer it becomes active
                    again, appearing in the sky as thunder and lightning. As a result the creative
                    forces on earth begin to stir again.
                      Here this creative force is still hidden beneath the earth and therefore has
                    no effect. In terms of human affairs, this symbolizes a great man who is still
                    unrecognized. Nonetheless he remains true to himself. He does not allow
                    himself to be influenced by outward success or failure, but confident in his
                    strength, he bides his time. Hence it is wise for the man who consults the
                    oracle and draws this line to wait in the calm strength of patience. The time
                    will fulfill itself.  One need not fear least strong will should not prevail; the
                    main thing is not to expend one's powers prematurely in an attempt to obtain
                    by force something for which the time is not yet ripe.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Dragon appearing in the field.
                    It furthers one to see the great man.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the effects of the light-giving power begin to manifest themselves. In
                    terms of human affairs, this means that the great man makes his appearance
                    in his chosen field of activity. As yet he has no commanding position but is
                    still with his peers. However, what distinguishes him form the others is his
                    seriousness of purpose, his unqualified reliability, and the influence he exerts
                    on his environment without conscious effort. Such a man is destined to
                    gain great influence and to set the world in order. Therefore it is favorable to
                    see him.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    All day long the superior man is creatively active.
                    At nightfall his mind is still beset with cares.
                    Danger. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A sphere of influence opens up for the great man. His fame begins to spread.
                    The masses flock to him. His inner power is adequate to the increased outer
                    activity. There are all sorts of things to be done, and when others are at rest in
                    the evening, plans and anxieties press in upon him. But danger lurks here at
                    the place of transition from lowliness to the heights. Many a great man has
                    been ruined because the masses flocked to him and swept him into their
                    course. Ambition has destroyed his integrity. However, true greatness is not
                    impaired by temptations. He who remains in touch with the time that is
                    dawning, and with its demands is prudent enough to avoid all pitfalls, and
                    remains blameless.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Wavering flight over the depths.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A place of transition has been reached, and free choice can enter in. A
                    twofold possibility is presented to the great man: he can soar to the heights
                    and play an important part in the world, or he can withdraw into solitude
                    and develop himself. He can go the way of the hero or that of the holy sage
                    who seeks seclusion. There is no general law of his being. If the individual
                    acts consistently and is true to himself, he will find the way that is appropriate
                    for him. This way is right for him and without blame.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Flying dragon in the heavens.
                    It furthers one to see the great man.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the great man has attained the sphere of the heavenly beings. His
                    influence spreads and becomes visible throughout the whole world.
                    Everyone who sees him may count himself blessed. Confucius says about this
                    line:

                    Things that accord in tone vibrate together. Things that have affinity in their
                    inmost natures seek one another. Water flows to what is wet, fire turns to
                    what is dry. Clouds (the breath of heaven) follow the dragon, wind (the breath
                    of earth) follows the tiger. Thus the sage arises, and all creatures follow him
                    with their eyes. What is born of heaven feels related to what is above. What
                    is born of earth feels related to what is below. Each follows its kind.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Arrogant dragon will have cause to repent.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When a man seeks to climb so high that he loses touch with the rest of
                    mankind, he becomes isolated, and this necessarily leads to failure. This line
                    warns against titanic aspirations that exceed one's power. A precipitous fall
                    would follow.
                </meaning>
            </six>
            <all>
                <text>
                    There appears a flight of dragons without heads.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When all the lines are nines, it means that the whole hexagram is in motion
                    and changes into the hexagram K'un, THE RECEPTIVE, whose character is
                    devotion. The strength of the Creative and the mildness of the Receptive
                    unite. Strength is indicated by the flight of dragons, mildness by the fact that
                    their heads are hidden. This means that mildness in action joined to strength
                    of decision brings good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </all>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Receptive" number="2">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of broken lines only. The broken lines represents
            the dark, yielding, receptive primal power of yin. The attribute of the
            hexagram is devotion; its image is the earth.  It is the perfect complement of
            THE CREATIVE— the complement, not the opposite, for the Receptive does
            not combat the Creative but completes it . It represents nature in contrast to
            spirit, earth in contrast to heaven, space as against time, the female-maternal
            as against the male-paternal. However, as applied to human affairs, the
            principle of this complementary relationship is found not only in the relation
            between man and woman, but also in that between prince and minister and
            between father and son. Indeed, even in the individual this duality appears
            in the coexistence of the spiritual world and the world of the senses.
              But strictly speaking there is no real dualism here, because there is a clearly
            defined hierarchic relationship between the two principles. In itself of course
            the Receptive is just as important as the Creative, but the attribute of
            devotion defines the place occupied by this primal power in relation to the
            Creative. For the Receptive must be activated and led by the Creative; then it
            is productive of good. Only when it abandons this position and tries to stand
            as an equal side by side with the Creative, does it become evil.  The result
            then is opposition to and struggle against the Creative, which is productive of
            evil to both.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE RECEPTIVE brings about sublime success,
                Furthering through the perseverance of a mare.
                If the superior man undertakes something and tries to lead,
                He goes astray;
                But if he follows, he finds guidance.
                It is favorable to find friends in the west and south,
                To forego friends in the east and north.
                Quiet perseverance brings good fortune.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The four fundamental aspects of the Creative— "sublime success, furthering
                through perseverance"— are also attributed to the Receptive.  Here, however,
                the perseverance is more closely defined: it is that of a mare. The Receptive
                connotes spatial reality in contrast to the spiritual potentiality of the Creative.
                The potential becomes real and the spiritual becomes spatial through a
                specifically qualifying definition. Thus the qualification, "of a mare," is here
                added to the idea of perseverance. The horse belongs to earth just as the
                dragon belongs to heaven. Its tireless roaming over the plains is taken as a
                symbol of the vast expanse of the earth. This is the symbol chosen because
                the mare combines the strength and swiftness of the horse with the
                gentleness and devotion of the cow.
                  Only because nature in its myriad forms corresponds with the myriad
                impulses of the Creative can it make these impulses real. Nature's richness
                lies in its power to nourish all living things; its greatness lies in its power to
                give then beauty and splendor. Thus it prospers all that lives. IT is the
                Creative that begets things, but they are brought to birth by the Receptive.
                Applied to human affairs, therefore, what the hexagram indicated is action in
                conformity with the situation. The person in questions not in an
                independent position, but is acting as an assistant. This means that he must
                achieve something. It is not his task to try to lead— that would only make him
                lose the way-but to let himself be led. If he knows how to meet fate with an
                attitude of acceptance, he is sure to find the right guidance. The superior man
                lets himself be guided; he does not go ahead blindly, but learns from the
                situation what is demanded of him and then follows this intimation from
                fate.
                  Since there is something to be accomplished, we need friends and helpers in
                the hour of toil and effort, once the ideas to be realized are firmly set. The
                time of toil and effort is indicated by the west and south, for west and south
                symbolize the place where the Receptive works for the Creative, as nature
                does in summer and autumn. If in that situation one does not mobilize all
                one's powers, the work to be accomplished will not be done. Hence to find
                friends there means to find guidance. But in addition to the time of toil and
                effort, there is also a time of planning, and for this we need this solitude. The
                east symbolized the place where a man receives orders from his master, and
                the north the place where he reports on what he has done. At that time he
                must be alone and objective. In this sacred hour he must do without
                companions. So that the purity of the moment may not be spoiled by fictional
                hates and favoritism.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The earth's condition is receptive devotion.
                Thus the superior man who has breadth of character
                Carries the outer world.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Just as there is only one heaven, so too there is only one earth. In the
                hexagram of heaven the doubling of the trigram implies duration in time,
                but in the hexagram of earth the doubling connotes the solidity and extension
                in space by virtue of which the earth is able to carry and preserve all things
                that live and move upon it. The earth in its devotion carries all things, good
                and evil,, without exception. In the same way the superior man gives to his
                character breadth, purity, and sustaining power, so that he is able both to
                support and to bear with people and things.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    When there is hoarfrost underfoot,
                    Solid ice is not far off.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Just as the light-giving power represents life, so the dark power, the shadowy,
                    represents death. When the first hoarfrost comes in the autumn, the power
                    of darkness and cold is just at its beginning. After these first warnings, signs
                    of death will gradually multiply, until, in obedience to immutable laws, stark
                    winter with its ice is here.
                      In life it is the same. After certain scarcely noticeable signs of decay have
                    appeared, they go on increasing until final dissolution comes. But in life
                    precautions can be taken by heeding the first signs of decay and checking them
                    in time.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Straight, square, great.
                    Without purpose,
                    Yet nothing remains unfurthered.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The symbol of heaven is the circle, and that of earth is the square. Thus
                    squareness is a primary quality of the earth. On the other hand, movement
                    in a straight line, as well as magnitude, is a primary quality of the Creative.
                    But all square things have their origin in a straight line and into turn form
                    solid bodies. In mathematics, when we discriminate between lines, planes
                    and solids, we find that rectangular planes result from straight lines, and
                    cubic magnitudes from rectangular planes. The Receptive accommodates
                    itself to the qualities of the Creative and makes them its own. Thus a square
                    develops out of a straight line and a cube out of a square. This is compliance
                    with the laws of the Creative; nothing is taken away, nothing added.
                    Therefore the Receptive has no need of a special purpose of its own, nor of
                    any effort' yet everything turns out as it should.
                      Nature creates all beings without erring: this is its foursquareness. It
                    tolerates all creatures equally: this is its greatness. Therefore it attains what is
                    right for all without artifice or special intentions. Man achieves the height of
                    wisdom when all that he does is as self-evident as what nature does.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Hidden lines.
                    One is able to remain persevering.
                    If by chance you are in the service of a king,
                    Seek not works, but bring to completion.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a man is free of vanity he is able to conceal his abilities and keep them from
                    attracting attention too soon; thus he can mature undisturbed.  If conditions
                    demand it, he can also enter public life, but that too he does with restraint.
                    The wise man gladly leaves fame to others. He does not seek to have credited
                    to himself things that stand accomplished, but hopes to release active forces;
                    that is, he completes his works in such a manner that they may bear fruit for
                    the future.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    A tied-up sack. No blame, no praise.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The dark element opens when it moves and closes when at rest. The strictest
                    reticence is indicated here. The time is dangerous , because any degree of
                    prominence leads either to the enmity of irresistible antagonists if one
                    challenges them or to misconceived recognition if one is complaisant.
                    Therefore a man ought to maintain reserve, be it in solitude or in the turmoil
                    of the world, for there too he can hide himself so well that no one knows
                    him.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    A yellow lower garment brings supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Yellow is the color of the earth and of the middle; it is the symbol of that
                    which is reliable and genuine. The lower garment is inconspicuously
                    decorated— the symbol of aristocratic reserve. When anyone is called upon to
                    work in a prominent but not independent position, true success depends on
                    the utmost discretion. A man's genuineness and refinement should not
                    reveal themselves directly; they should express themselves only indirectly as
                    an effect from within.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Dragons fight in the meadow.
                    Their blood is black and yellow.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the top place the dark element should yield to the light. If it attempts to
                    maintain a position to which it is not entitled and to rule instead of serving,
                    it draws down upon itself the anger of the strong. A struggle ensues in which
                    it is overthrown, with injury, however, to both sides. The dragon, symbol of
                    heaven, comes to fight the false dragon that symbolized the inflation of the
                    earth principle. Midnight blue is the color of heaven; yellow is the color of
                    earth. Therefore, when black and yellow blood flow, it is a sign that in this
                    unnatural contest both primal powers suffer injury.
                </meaning>
            </six>
            <all>
                <text>
                    When all the lines are sixes, it means:
                    Lasting perseverance furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When nothing but sixes appears, the hexagram of THE RECEPTIVE changes
                    into the hexagram of THE CREATIVE. By holding fast to what is right, it
                    gains the power of enduring. There is indeed no advance, but neither is there
                    retrogression.
                </meaning>
            </all>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Difficulty at the Beginning" number="3">
        <description>
                The name of the hexagram, Chun, really connotes a blade of grass pushing
                against an obstacle as it sprouts out of the earth— hence the meaning,
                "difficulty at the beginning." The hexagram indicates the way in which
                heaven and earth bring forth individual beings. It is their first meeting,
                which is beset with difficulties. The lower trigram Chên is the Arousing; its
                motion is upward and its image is thunder. The upper trigram K'an stands
                for the Abysmal, the dangerous. Its motion is downward and its image is
                rain. The situation points to teeming, chaotic profusion; thunder and rain fill
                the air. But the chaos clears up. While the Abysmal sinks, the upward
                movement eventually passes beyond the danger. A thunderstorm brings
                release from tension, and all things breathe freely again.
            </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                DIFFICULTY AT THE BEGINNING works supreme success,
                Furthering through perseverance.
                Nothing should be undertaken.
                It furthers one to appoint helpers.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Times of growth are beset with difficulties. They resemble a first birth. But
                these difficulties arise from the very profusion of all that is struggling to
                attain form . Everything is in motion: therefore if one perseveres there is a
                prospect of great success, in spite of the existing danger. When it is a man's
                fate to undertake such new beginnings, everything is still unformed, dark.
                Hence he must hold back, because any premature move might bring disaster.
                Likewise, it is very important not to remain alone; in order to overcome the
                chaos he needs helpers. This is not to say, however, that he himself should
                look on passively at what is happening. He must lend his hand and
                participate with inspiration and guidance.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Clouds and thunder:
                The image of DIFFICULTY AT THE BEGINNING.
                Thus the superior man
                Brings order out of confusion.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Clouds and thunder are represented by definite decorative lines; this means
                that in the chaos of difficulty at the beginning, order is already implicit. So
                too the superior man has to arrange and organize the inchoate profusion of
                such times of beginning, just as one sorts out silk threads from a knotted
                tangle and binds them into skeins. In order to find one's place in the infinity
                of being, one must be able both to separate and to unite.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Hesitation and hindrance.
                    It furthers one to remain persevering.
                    It furthers one to appoint helpers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a person encounters a hindrance at the beginning of an enterprise, he must
                    not try to force advance but must pause and take thought. However, nothing
                    should put him off his course; he must persevere and constantly keep the
                    goal in sight. It is important to seek out the right assistants, but he can find
                    them only if he avoids arrogance and associated with his fellows in a spirit of
                    humility. Only then will he attract those with whose help he can combat the
                    difficulties.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Difficulties pile up.
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    He is not a robber;
                    He wants to woo when the time comes.
                    The maiden is chaste,
                    She does not pledge herself.
                    Ten years— then she pledges herself.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We find ourselves beset by difficulties and hindrances. Suddenly there is a
                    turn of affairs, as if someone were coming up with a horse and wagon and
                    unhitching them. This event comes so unexpectedly that we assume the
                    newcomer to be a robber. Gradually it becomes clear that he has no evil
                    intentions but seeks to be friendly and to offer help. But this offer is not to be
                    accepted, because it does not come from the right quarter. We must wait until
                    the time is fulfilled; ten years is a fulfilled cycle of time. Then normal
                    conditions return of themselves, and we can join forces with the friend
                    intended for us.
                      Using the image of a betrothed girl who remains true to her lover in face of
                    grave conflicts, the hexagram gives counsel for a special situation. When in
                    times of difficulty a hindrance is encountered and unexpected relief is offered
                    from a source unrelated to us, we must be careful and not take upon
                    ourselves any obligations entailed by such help; otherwise our freedom of
                    decision is impaired. If we bide our time, things will quiet down again, and
                    we shall attain what we have hoped for.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Whoever hunts deer without the forester
                    Only loses his way in the forest.
                    The superior man understands the signs of the time
                    And prefers to desist.
                    To go on brings humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a man tries to hunt in a strange forest and has no guide, he loses his way.
                    When he finds himself in difficulties he must not try to steal out of them
                    unthinkingly and without guidance. Fate cannot be duped; premature effort,
                    without the necessary guidance, ends in failure and disgrace.  Therefore the
                    superior man, discerning the seeds of coming events, prefers to renounce a
                    wish rather than to provoke failure and humiliation by trying to force its
                    fulfillment.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    Strive for union.
                    To go brings good fortune.
                    Everything acts to further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We are in a situation in which it is our duty to act, but we lack sufficient
                    power. However, an opportunity to make connections offers itself. It must be
                    seized. Neither false pride nor false reserve should deter us. Bringing oneself
                    to take the first step, even when it involves a certain degree of self-
                    abnegation, is a sign of inner clarity. To accept help in a difficult situation is
                    not a disgrace. If the right helper is found, all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Difficulties in blessing.
                    A little perseverance brings good fortune.
                    Great perseverance brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An individual is in a position in which he cannot so express his good
                    intentions that they will actually take shape and be understood. Other people
                    interpose and distort everything he does. He should then be cautious and
                    proceed step by step. He must not try to force the consummation of a great
                    undertaking, because success is possible only when general confidence already
                    prevails. It is only through faithful and conscientious work, unobtrusively
                    carried on, that the situation gradually clears up and the hindrance
                    disappears.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Horse and wagon part.
                    Bloody tears flow.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The difficulties at the beginning are too great for some persons. They get
                    stuck and never find their way out; they fold their hands and give up the
                    struggle. Such resignation is the saddest of all things. Therefore Confucius
                    says of this line: "Bloody tears flow: one should not persist in this."
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Youthful Folly" number="4">
        <description>
            In this hexagram we are reminded of youth and folly in two different ways.
            The image of the upper trigram, Kên, is the mountain, that of the lower,
            K'an, is water; the spring rising at the foot of the mountain is the image of
            inexperienced youth. Keeping still is the attribute of the upper trigram; that of
            the lower is the abyss, danger. Stopping in perplexity on the brink of a
            dangerous abyss is a symbol of the folly of youth. However, the two trigrams
            also show the way of overcoming the follies of youth. Water is something
            that of necessity flows on. When the spring gushes forth, it does not know at
            first where it will go. But its steady flow fills up the deep place blocking its
            progress, and success is attained.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                YOUTHFUL FOLLY has success.
                It is not I who seek the young fool;
                The young fool seeks me.
                At the first oracle I inform him.
                If he asks two or three times, it is importunity.
                If he importunes, I give him no information.
                Perseverance furthers.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In the time of youth, folly is not an evil. One may succeed in spite of it,
                provided one finds an experienced teacher and has the right attitude toward
                him. This means, first of all, that the youth himself must be conscious of his
                lack of experience and must seek out the teacher. Without this modesty and
                this interest there is no guarantee that he has the necessary receptivity, which
                should express itself in respectful acceptance of the teacher. This is the reason
                why the teacher must wait to be sought out instead of offering himself. Only
                thus can the instruction take place at the right time and in the right way.
                  A teacher's answer to the question of a pupil ought to be clear and definite
                like that expected from an oracle; thereupon it ought to be accepted as a key
                for resolution of doubts and a basis for decision. If mistrustful or
                unintelligent questioning is kept up, it serves only to annoy the teacher. He
                does well to ignore it in silence, just as the oracle gives one answer only and
                refuses to be tempted by questions implying doubt.
                  Given addition a perseverance that never slackens until the points are
                mastered one by one, real success is sure to follow. Thus the hexagram
                counsels the teacher as well as the pupil.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                A spring wells up at the foot of the mountain:
                The image of YOUTH.
                Thus the superior man fosters his character
                By thoroughness in all that he does.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                A spring succeeds in flowing on and escapes stagnation by filling up all the
                hollow places in its path. In the same way character is developed by
                thoroughness that skips nothing but, like water, gradually and steadily fills up
                all gaps and so flows onward.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    To make a fool develop
                    It furthers one to apply discipline.
                    The fetters should be removed.
                    To go on in this way bring humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Law is the beginning of education. Youth in its inexperience is inclined at first
                    to take everything carelessly and playfully.  It must be shown the seriousness
                    of life. A certain measure of taking oneself in hand, brought about by strict
                    discipline, is a good thing. He who plays with life never amounts to
                    anything. However, discipline should not degenerate into drill. Continuous
                    drill has a humiliating effect and cripples a man's powers.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    To bear with fools in kindliness brings good fortune.
                    To know how to take women
                    Brings good fortune.
                    The son is capable of taking charge of the household.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    These lines picture a man who has no external power, but who has enough
                    strength of mind to bear his burden of responsibility. He has the inner
                    superiority and that enable him to tolerate with kindliness the shortcomings
                    of human folly. The same attitude is owed to women as the weaker sex. One
                    must understand them and give them recognition in a spirit of chivalrous
                    consideration. Only this combination of inner strength with outer reserve
                    enables one to take on the responsibility of directing a larger social body with
                    real success.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Take not a maiden who. When she sees a man of bronze,
                    Loses possession of herself.
                    Nothing furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A weak, inexperienced man, struggling to rise, easily loses his own
                    individuality when he slavishly imitates a strong personality of higher
                    station. He is like a girl throwing herself away when she meets a strong man.
                    Such a servile approach should not be encouraged, because it is bad both for
                    the youth and the teacher. A girl owes it to her dignity to wait until she is
                    wooed. In both cases it is undignified to offer oneself, and no good comes of
                    accepting such an offer.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Entangled folly bring humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    For youthful folly it is the most hopeless thing to entangle itself in empty
                    imaginings. The more obstinately it clings to such unreal fantasies, the more
                    certainly will humiliation overtake it.
                     Often the teacher, when confronted with such entangled folly, has no other
                    course but to leave the fool to himself for a time, not sparing him the
                    humiliation that results. This is frequently the only means of rescue.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Childlike folly brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An inexperienced person who seeks instruction in a childlike and
                    unassuming way is on the right path, for the man devoid of arrogance who
                    subordinated himself to his teacher will certainly be helped.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    In punishing folly
                    It does not further one
                    To commit transgressions.
                    The only thing that furthers
                    Is to prevent transgressions.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Sometimes an incorrigible fool must be punished. He who will not heed will
                    be made to feel. This punishment is quite different from a preliminary
                    shaking up. But the penalty should not be imposed in anger; it must be
                    restricted to an objective guarding against unjustified excesses. Punishment
                    is never an end in itself but serves merely to restore order.
                      This applies not only in regard to education but also in regard to the
                    measures taken by a government against a populace guilty of transgressions.
                    Governmental interference should always be merely preventive and should
                    have as its sole aim the establishment of public security and peace.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Waiting (Nourishment)" number="5">
        <description>
            All beings have need of nourishment from above. But the gift of food comes
            in its own time, and for this one must wait. This hexagram shows the clouds
            in the heavens, giving rain to refresh all that grows and to provide mankind
            with food and drink. The rain will come in its own time. We cannot make it
            come; we have to wait for it. The idea of waiting is further suggested by the
            attributes of the two trigrams— strength within, danger in from. Strength in
            the face of danger does not plunge ahead but bides its time, whereas weakness
            in the face of danger grows agitated and has not the patience to wait.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                WAITING. If you are sincere,
                You have light and success.
                Perseverance brings good fortune.
                It furthers one to cross the great water.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Waiting is not mere empty hoping. It has the inner certainty of reaching the
                goal. Such certainty alone gives that light which leads to success. This leads
                to the perseverance that brings good fortune and bestows power to cross the
                great water. One is faced with a danger that has to be overcome. Weakness
                and impatience can do nothing. Only a strong man can stand up to his fate,
                for his inner security enables him to endure to the end. This strength shows
                itself in uncompromising truthfulness [with himself]. It is only when we
                have the courage to face things exactly as they are, without any sort of self-
                deception or illusion, that a light will develop out of events, by which the
                path to success may be recognized. This recognition must be followed by
                resolute and persevering action. For only the man who goes to meet his fate
                resolutely is equipped to deal with it adequately. Then he will be able to cross
                the great water— that is to say, he will be capable of making the necessary
                decision and of surmounting the danger.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Clouds rise up to heaven:
                The image of WAITING.
                Thus the superior man eats and drinks,
                Is joyous and of good cheer.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When clouds rise in the sky, it is a sign that it will rain. There is nothing to
                do but to wait until after the rain falls. It is the same in life when destiny is at
                work. We should not worry and seek to shape the future by interfering in
                things before the time is ripe. We should quietly fortify the body with food
                and drink and the mind with gladness and good cheer. Fate comes when it
                will, and thus we are ready.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Waiting in the meadow.
                    IT furthers one to abide in what endures.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The danger is not yet close. One is still waiting on the open plain.
                    Conditions are still simple, yet there is a feeling of something impending.
                    One must continue to lead a regular life as long as possible. Only in this way
                    does one guard against a premature waste of strength, keep free of blame and
                    error that would become a source of weakness later on.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Waiting on the sand.
                    There is some gossip.
                    The end brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The danger gradually comes closer. Sand is near the bank of the river, and
                    the water means danger. Disagreements crop up. General unrest can easily
                    develop in such times, and we lay the blame on one another. He who stays
                    calm will succeed in making things go well in the end. Slander will be
                    silenced if we do not gratify it with injured retorts.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Waiting in the mud
                    Brings about the arrival of the enemy.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Mud is no place for waiting, since it is already being washed by the water of
                    the stream. Instead of having gathered strength to cross the stream at one try,
                    one has made a premature start that has got him no farther than the muddy
                    bank. Such an unfavorable position invites enemies from without, who
                    naturally take advantage of it. Caution and a sense of the seriousness of the
                    situation are all that can keep one from injury.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Waiting in blood.
                    Get out of the pit.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The situation is extremely dangerous. IT is of utmost gravity now— a matter
                    of life and death. Bloodshed seems imminent. There is no going forward or
                    backward; we are cut off as if in a pit. Now we must simply stand fast and let
                    fate take its course. This composure, which keeps us from aggravating the
                    trouble by anything we might do, is the only way of getting out of the
                    dangerous pit.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Waiting at meat and drink.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Even in the midst of danger there come intervals of peace when things go
                    relatively well. If we possess enough inner strength, we shall take advantage
                    of these intervals to fortify ourselves for renewed struggle. We must know
                    how to enjoy the moment without being deflected from the goal, for
                    perseverance is needed to remain victorious.
                      This is true in public life as well; it is not possible to achieve everything all
                    at once. The height of wisdom is to allow people enough recreation to
                    quicken pleasure in their work until the task is completed. Herein lies the
                    secret of the whole hexagram. It differs from Chin OBSTRUCTION (39), in
                    the fact that in this instance, while waiting, we are sure of our cause and
                    therefore do not lose the serenity born of inner cheerfulness.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    One falls into the pit.
                    Three uninvited guests arrive.
                    Honor them, and in the end there will be good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The waiting is over; the danger can no longer be averted.  One falls into the
                    pit and must yield to the inevitable. Everything seems to have been in vain.
                    But precisely in this extremity things take an unforeseen turn.  Without a
                    move on one's own part, there is outside intervention. At first one cannot be
                    sure of its meaning: is it rescue or is it destruction? A person in this
                    situation must keep his mind alert and not withdraw into himself with a
                    sulky gesture of refusal, but must greet the new turn with respect. Thus he
                    ultimately escapes the danger, and all goes well. Even happy turns of fortune
                    often come in a form that at first seems strange to us.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Conflict" number="6">
        <description>
            The upper trigram, whose image is heaven, has an upward movement; the
            lower trigram, water, in accordance with its nature tends downward. Thus the
            two halves move away from each other, giving rise to the idea of conflict.
              The attribute of the Creative is strength, that of the Abysmal is danger, guile.
            Where cunning has force before it, there is conflict.
              A third indication of conflict, in terms of character, is presented by the
            combination of deep cunning within and fixed determination outwardly. A
            person of this character will certainly be quarrelsome.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                CONFLICT. You are sincere
                And are being obstructed.
                A cautious halt halfway brings good fortune.
                Going through to the end brings misfortune.
                It furthers one to see the great man.
                It does not further one to cross the great water.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Conflict develops when one feels himself to be in the right and runs into
                opposition. If one is not convinced of being in the right, opposition leads to
                craftiness or high-handed encroachment but not to open conflict.
                  If a man is entangled in a conflict, his only salvation lies in being so clear-
                headed and inwardly strong that he is always ready to come to terms by
                meeting the opponent halfway. To carry one the conflict to the bitter end has
                evil effects even when one is the right, because the enmity is then
                perpetuated. It is important to see the great man, that is, an impartial man
                whose authority is great enough to terminate the conflict amicably or assure a
                just decision. In times of strife, crossing the great water is to be avoided, that
                is, dangerous enterprises are not to be begun, because in order to be successful
                they require concerted unity of focus. Conflict within weakens the power to
                conquer danger without.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven and water go their opposite ways:
                The image of CONFLICT.
                Thus in all his transactions the superior man
                Carefully considers the beginning.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The image indicates that the causes of conflict are latent in the opposing
                tendencies of the two trig rams. Once these opposing tendencies appear,
                conflict is inevitable. To avoid it, therefore, everything must be taken
                carefully into consideration in the very beginning. If rights and duties are
                exactly defined, or if, in a group, the spiritual trends of the individuals
                harmonize, the cause of conflict is removed in advance.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    If one does not perpetuate the affair,
                    There is a little gossip.
                    In the end, good fortune comes.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    While a conflict is in the incipient stage, the best thing To do is to drop the
                    issue. Especially when the adversary is stronger, it is not advisable to risk
                    pushing the conflict to a decision. It may come to a slight dispute, but in the
                    end all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    One cannot engage in conflict;
                    One returns home, gives way.
                    The people of his town,
                    Three hundred households,
                    Remain free of guilt.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In a struggle with an enemy of superior strength, retreat is no disgrace.
                    Timely withdrawal prevents bad consequences. If, out of a false sense of
                    honor, a man allowed himself to be tempted into an unequal conflict, he
                    would be drawing down disaster upon himself. In such a case a wise and
                    conciliatory attitude benefits the whole community, which will then not be
                    drawn into the conflict.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    To nourish oneself on ancient virtue induces perseverance.
                    Danger. In the end, good fortune comes.
                    If by chance you are in the service of a king,
                    Seek not works.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This is a warning of the danger that goes with an expansive disposition. Only
                    that which has been honestly acquired through merit remains a permanent
                    possession. It can happen that such a possession may be contested, but since it
                    is really one's own, one cannot be robbed of it. Whatever a man possesses
                    through the strength of his own nature cannot be lost. If one enters the
                    service of a superior, one can avoid conflict only by not seeking works for the
                    sake of prestige. It is enough if the work is done: let the honor go to the
                    other.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    One cannot engage in conflict.
                    One turns back and submits to fate,
                    Changes one's attitude,
                    And finds peace in perseverance.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to a person whose inner attitude at first lacks peace. He does not
                    feel content with his situation and would like to improve it through conflict.
                    In contrast tot the situation of the nine in the second place, he is dealing with
                    a weaker opponent and might therefore succeed. But he cannot carry on the
                    fight, because, since right is not on his side, he cannot justify the conflict to
                    his conscience. Therefore he turns back and accepts his fate. He changes his
                    mind and finds lasting peace in being at one with eternal law. This brings
                    good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    To contend before him
                    Brings supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to an arbiter in a conflict who is powerful and just, and strong
                    enough to lend weight to the right side. A dispute can be turned over to him
                    with confidence. If one is in the right, one attains great good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Even if by chance a leather belt is bestowed on one,'
                    By the end of a morning
                    It will have been snatched away three times.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here we have someone who has carried a conflict to the bitter end and has
                    triumphed. He is granted a decoration, but his happiness does not last.  He is
                    attacked again and again, and the result is conflict without end.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Army" number="7">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of the trigrams K'an, water, and K'un, earth, and
            thus it symbolizes the ground water stored up in the earth. In the same way
            military strength is stored up in the mass of the people— invisible in times of
            peace but always ready for use as a source of power. The attributes of the two
            trig rams are danger inside and obedience must prevail outside.
              Of the individual lines, the one that controls the hexagram is the strong
            nine in the second place, to which the other lines, all yielding, are
            subordinate. This line indicates a commander, because it stands in the
            middle of one of the two trigrams. But since it is in the lower rather than the
            upper trigram, it represents not the ruler but the efficient general, who
            maintains obedience in the army by his authority.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE ARMY. The army needs perseverance
                And a strong man.
                Good fortune without blame.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                An army is a mass that needs organization in order to become a fighting force.
                Without strict discipline nothing can be accomplished, but this discipline
                must not be achieved by force. It requires a strong man who captures the
                hearts of the people and awakens their enthusiasm. In order that he may
                develop his abilities he needs the complete confidence of his ruler, who must
                entrust him with full responsibility as long as the war lasts. But war is always
                a dangerous thing and brings with it destruction and devastation. Therefore
                it should not be resorted to rashly but, like a poisonous drug, should be used
                as a last recourse.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                In the middle of the earth is water:
                The image of THE ARMY.
                Thus the superior man increases his masses
                By generosity toward the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Ground water is invisibly present within the earth. In the same way the
                military power of a people is invisibly present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes a soldier; when the war ends, he goes back
                to his plow. He who is generous toward the people wins their love, and a
                people living under a mild rule becomes strong and powerful. Only a people
                economically strong can be important in military power. Such power must
                therefore be cultivated by improving the economic condition of the people
                and by humane government. Only when there is this invisible bond between
                government and people, so that the people are sheltered by their
                government as ground water is sheltered by the earth, is it possible to wage a
                victorious war.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    An army must set forth in proper order.
                    If the order is not good, misfortune threatens.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    At the beginning of a military enterprise, order is imperative. A just and
                    valid cause must exist, and the obedience and coordination of the troops must
                    be well organized, otherwise the result is inevitably failure.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    In the midst of the army.
                    Good fortune. No blame.
                    The king bestows a triple decoration.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The leader should be in the midst of his army, in touch with it, sharing good
                    and bad with the masses he leads. This alone makes him equal to the heavy
                    demands made upon him. He needs also the recognition of the ruler. The
                    decorations he receives are justified, because there is no question of personal
                    preferment here: the whole army, whose center he is, is honored in his
                    person.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Perchance the army carries corpses in the wagon.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here we have a choice of two explanations. One points to defeat because
                    someone other than the chosen leader interferes with the command; the
                    other is similar in its general meaning, but the expression, "carries corpses in
                    the wagon," is interpreted differently. At burials and at sacrifices to the dead it
                    was customary in China for the deceased to whom the sacrifice was made to
                    be represented by a boy of the family, who sat in the dead man's place and was
                    honored as his representative. On the basis of this custom the text is
                    interpreted as meaning that a "corpse boy" is sitting in the wagon, or, in
                    other words, that authority is not being exercised by the proper leaders but has
                    been usurped by others. Perhaps the whole difficulty clears up if it is inferred
                    that there has been an error in copying. The character fan, meaning "all," may
                    have been misread as shih, which means "corpse." Allowing for this error,
                    the meaning would be that if the multitude assumes leadership of the army
                    (rides in the wagon), misfortune will ensue.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The army retreats. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the face of a superior enemy, with whom it would be hopeless to engage in
                    battle, an orderly retreat is the only correct procedure, because it will save the
                    army from defeat and disintegration. It is by no means a sign of courage or
                    strength to insist upon engaging in a hopeless struggle regardless of
                    circumstances.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    There is game in the field.
                    It furthers one to catch it.
                    Without blame.
                    Let the eldest lead the army.
                    The younger transports corpses;
                    Then perseverance brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Game is in the field— it has left its usual haunts in the forest and is
                    devastating the fields. This points to an enemy invasion. Energetic combat
                    and punishment are here thoroughly justified, but they must not degenerate
                    into a wild melee in which everyone fends for himself. Despite the greatest
                    degree of perseverance and bravery, this would lead to misfortune. The army
                    must be directed by an experienced leader. It is a matter of waging war, not of
                    permitting the mob to slaughter all who fall into their hands; if they do,
                    defeat will be the result, and despite all perseverance there is danger of
                    misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The great prince issues commands,
                    Founds states, vests families with fiefs.
                    Inferior people should not be employed.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The war has ended successfully, victory is won, and the king divided estates
                    and fiefs among his faithful vassals. But it is important that inferior people
                    should not come into power. If they have helped, let them be paid off with
                    money, but they should not be awarded lands or the privileges of rulers, lest
                    power be abused.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="7">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of the trigrams K'an, water, and K'un, earth, and
            thus it symbolizes the ground water stored up in the earth. In the same way
            military strength is stored up in the mass of the people— invisible in times of
            peace but always ready for use as a source of power. The attributes of the two
            trig rams are danger inside and obedience must prevail outside.
              Of the individual lines, the one that controls the hexagram is the strong
            nine in the second place, to which the other lines, all yielding, are
            subordinate. This line indicates a commander, because it stands in the
            middle of one of the two trigrams. But since it is in the lower rather than the
            upper trigram, it represents not the ruler but the efficient general, who
            maintains obedience in the army by his authority.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE ARMY. The army needs perseverance
                And a strong man.
                Good fortune without blame.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                An army is a mass that needs organization in order to become a fighting force.
                Without strict discipline nothing can be accomplished, but this discipline
                must not be achieved by force. It requires a strong man who captures the
                hearts of the people and awakens their enthusiasm. In order that he may
                develop his abilities he needs the complete confidence of his ruler, who must
                entrust him with full responsibility as long as the war lasts. But war is always
                a dangerous thing and brings with it destruction and devastation. Therefore
                it should not be resorted to rashly but, like a poisonous drug, should be used
                as a last recourse.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                In the middle of the earth is water:
                The image of THE ARMY.
                Thus the superior man increases his masses
                By generosity toward the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Ground water is invisibly present within the earth. In the same way the
                military power of a people is invisibly present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes present in the masses. When danger
                threatens, every peasant becomes a soldier; when the war ends, he goes back
                to his plow. He who is generous toward the people wins their love, and a
                people living under a mild rule becomes strong and powerful. Only a people
                economically strong can be important in military power. Such power must
                therefore be cultivated by improving the economic condition of the people
                and by humane government. Only when there is this invisible bond between
                government and people, so that the people are sheltered by their
                government as ground water is sheltered by the earth, is it possible to wage a
                victorious war.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    An army must set forth in proper order.
                    If the order is not good, misfortune threatens.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    At the beginning of a military enterprise, order is imperative. A just and
                    valid cause must exist, and the obedience and coordination of the troops must
                    be well organized, otherwise the result is inevitably failure.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    In the midst of the army.
                    Good fortune. No blame.
                    The king bestows a triple decoration.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The leader should be in the midst of his army, in touch with it, sharing good
                    and bad with the masses he leads. This alone makes him equal to the heavy
                    demands made upon him. He needs also the recognition of the ruler. The
                    decorations he receives are justified, because there is no question of personal
                    preferment here: the whole army, whose center he is, is honored in his
                    person.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Perchance the army carries corpses in the wagon.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here we have a choice of two explanations. One points to defeat because
                    someone other than the chosen leader interferes with the command; the
                    other is similar in its general meaning, but the expression, "carries corpses in
                    the wagon," is interpreted differently. At burials and at sacrifices to the dead it
                    was customary in China for the deceased to whom the sacrifice was made to
                    be represented by a boy of the family, who sat in the dead man's place and was
                    honored as his representative. On the basis of this custom the text is
                    interpreted as meaning that a "corpse boy" is sitting in the wagon, or, in
                    other words, that authority is not being exercised by the proper leaders but has
                    been usurped by others. Perhaps the whole difficulty clears up if it is inferred
                    that there has been an error in copying. The character fan, meaning "all," may
                    have been misread as shih, which means "corpse." Allowing for this error,
                    the meaning would be that if the multitude assumes leadership of the army
                    (rides in the wagon), misfortune will ensue.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Six in the fourth place means:
                    The army retreats. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the face of a superior enemy, with whom it would be hopeless to engage in
                    battle, an orderly retreat is the only correct procedure, because it will save the
                    army from defeat and disintegration. It is by no means a sign of courage or
                    strength to insist upon engaging in a hopeless struggle regardless of
                    circumstances.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    There is game in the field.
                    It furthers one to catch it.
                    Without blame.
                    Let the eldest lead the army.
                    The younger transports corpses;
                    Then perseverance brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Game is in the field— it has left its usual haunts in the forest and is
                    devastating the fields. This points to an enemy invasion. Energetic combat
                    and punishment are here thoroughly justified, but they must not degenerate
                    into a wild melee in which everyone fends for himself. Despite the greatest
                    degree of perseverance and bravery, this would lead to misfortune. The army
                    must be directed by an experienced leader. It is a matter of waging war, not of
                    permitting the mob to slaughter all who fall into their hands; if they do,
                    defeat will be the result, and despite all perseverance there is danger of
                    misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The great prince issues commands,
                    Founds states, vests families with fiefs.
                    Inferior people should not be employed.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The war has ended successfully, victory is won, and the king divided estates
                    and fiefs among his faithful vassals. But it is important that inferior people
                    should not come into power. If they have helped, let them be paid off with
                    money, but they should not be awarded lands or the privileges of rulers, lest
                    power be abused.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Holding Together (Union)" number="8">
        <description>
            The waters on the surface of the earth flow together wherever they can, as for
            example in the ocean, where all the rivers come together. Symbolically this
            connotes holding together and the laws that regulate it. The same idea is
            suggested by the fact that all the lines of the hexagram except the fifth, the
            place of the ruler, are yielding. The yielding lines hold together because they
            are influenced by a man of strong will in the leading position, a man who is
            their center of union. Moreover, this strong and guiding personality in turn
            holds together with the others, finding in them the complement of his own
            nature.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                HOLDING TOGETHER brings good fortune.
                Inquire of the oracle once again
                Whether you possess sublimity, constancy, and perseverance;
                Then there is no blame.
                Those who are uncertain gradually join.
                Whoever come too late
                Meets with misfortune.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                What is required is that we unite with others, in order that all may
                complement and aid one another through holding together. But such
                holding together calls for a central figure around whom other persons may
                unite. To become a center of influence holding people together is a grave
                matter and fraught with great responsibility. It requires greatness of spirit,
                consistency, and strength. Therefore let him who wishes to gather others
                about him ask himself whether he is equal to the undertaking, for anyone
                attempting the task without a real calling for it only makes confusion worse
                than if no union at all had taken place.
                  But when there is a real rallying point, those who at first are hesitant or
                uncertain gradually come in of their own accord. Late-comers must suffer the
                consequences, for in holding together the question of the right time is also
                important. Relationships are formed and firmly established according to
                definite inner laws. Common experiences strengthen these ties, and he who
                comes too late to share in these basic experiences must suffer for it if, as a
                straggler, he finds the door locked.
                  If a man has recognized the necessity for union and does not feel strong
                enough to function as the center, it is his duty to become a member of some
                other organic fellowship.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                On the earth is water:
                The image of HOLDING TOGETHER.
                Thus the kings of antiquity
                Bestowed the different states as fiefs
                And cultivated friendly relations
                With the feudal lords.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Water fills up all the empty places on the earth and clings fast to it. The social
                organization of ancient China was based on this principle of the holding
                together of dependents and rulers. Water flows to unite with water, because
                all parts of it are subject to the same laws. So too should human society hold
                together through a community of interests that allows each individual to feel
                himself a member of a whole. The central power of a social organization
                must see to it that every member finds that his true interest lies in holding
                together with it, as was the case in the paternal relationship between king and
                vassals in ancient China.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Hold to him in truth and loyalty;
                    This is without blame.
                    Truth, like a full earthen bowl"
                    Thus in the end
                    Good fortune comes from without.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Fundamental sincerity is the only proper basis for forming relationships.
                    This attitude, symbolized by a full earthen bowl, in which the content is
                    everything and the empty form nothing, shows itself not in clever words but
                    through the strength of what lies within the speaker. This strength is so great
                    that it has power to attract good fortune to itself from without.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Hold to him inwardly.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a person responds perseveringly and in the right way to the behests from
                    above that summon him to action, his relations with others are intrinsic and
                    he does not lose himself. But if a man seeks association with others as if he
                    were an obsequious office hunter, he throws himself away. He does not
                    follow the path of the superior man, who never loses his dignity.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    You hold together with the wrong people
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We are often among people who do not belong to our own sphere. In that
                    case we must beware of being drawn into false intimacy through force of
                    habit. Needless to say, this would have evil consequences. Maintaining
                    sociability without intimacy is the only right attitude toward people, because
                    otherwise we should not be free to enter into relationship with people of our
                    own kind later on.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Hold to him outwardly also.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the relations with a man who is the center of union are well established.
                    Then we may, and indeed we should, show our attachment openly. But we
                    must remain constant and not allow ourselves to be led astray.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Manifestation of holding together.
                    In the hunt the king uses beaters on three sides only
                    And forgoes game that runs off in front.
                    The citizens need no warning.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the royal hunts of ancient China it was customary to drive up the game
                    from three sides, but on the fourth the animals had a chance to run off. If
                    they failed to do this they had to pass through a gate behind which the king
                    stood ready to shoot. Only animals that entered here were shot; those that
                    ran off in front were permitted to escape. This custom accorded with a kingly
                    attitude; the royal hunter did not wish to turn the chase into a slaughter, but
                    held that the kill should consist only of those animals which had so to speak
                    voluntarily exposed themselves.
                      There is depicted here a ruler, or influential man, to whom people are
                    attracted. Those who come to him he accepts, those who do not come are
                    allowed to go their own way. He invited none, flatters none— all come of
                    their own free will. In this way there develops a voluntary dependence
                    among those who hold him. They do not have to be constantly on their
                    guard but may express their opinions openly. Police measures are not
                    necessary, and they cleave to their ruler of their own volition. The same
                    principle of freedom is valid for life in general. We should not woo favor
                    from people. If a man cultivates within himself the purity and the strength
                    that are necessary for one who is the center of a fellowship, those who are
                    meant for him come of their own accord.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    He finds no head for holding together.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The head is the beginning. If the beginning is not right, there is no hope of a
                    right ending. If we have missed the right moment for union and go on
                    hesitating to give complete and full devotion, we shall regret the error when
                    it is too late.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Taming Power of the Small" number="9">
        <description>
            This hexagram means the force of the small— the power of the shadowy— that
            restrains, tames, impedes. A weak line in the fourth place, that of the
            minister, holds the five strong lines in check. In the Image it is the wind
            blowing across the sky. The wind restrains the clouds, the rising breath of the
            Creative, and makes them grow dense, but as yet is not strong enough to turn
            them to rain. The hexagram presents a configuration of circumstances in
            which a strong element is temporarily held in leash by a weak element. It is
            only through gentleness that this can have a successful outcome.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE TAMING POWER OF THE SMALL
                Has success.
                Dense clouds, no rain from our western region.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                This image refers to the state of affairs in China at the time when King Wên,
                who came originally from the west, was in the east at the court of the reigning
                tyrant Chou Hsin. The moment for action on a large scale had not yet
                arrived. King Wên could only keep the tyrant somewhat in check by friendly
                persuasion. Hence the image of many clouds, promising moisture and
                blessing to the land, although as yet no rain falls. The situation is not
                unfavorable; there is a prospect of ultimate success, but there are still obstacles
                in the way, and we can merely take preparatory measures. Only through the
                small means of friendly persuasion can we exert any influence. The time has
                not yet come for sweeping measures. However, we may be able, to a limited
                extent, to act as a restraining and subduing influence. To carry out our
                purpose we need firm determination within and gentleness and adaptability
                in external relations.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The wind drives across heaven:
                The image of THE TAMING POWER OF THE SMALL.
                Thus the superior man
                Refines the outward aspect of his nature.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The wind can indeed drive the clouds together in the sky; yet, being nothing
                but air, without solid body, it does not produce great or lasting effects. So also
                an individual, in times when he can produce no great effect in the outer
                world, can do nothing except refine the expression of his nature in small
                ways.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Return to the way.
                    How could there be blame in this?
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It lies in the nature of a strong man to press forward. In so doing he
                    encounters obstructions. Therefore he returns to the way suited to his
                    situation, where he is free to advance or to retreat. In the nature of things
                    this will bring good fortune, for it is wise and reasonable not to try to obtain
                    anything by force.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    He allows himself to be drawn into returning.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    One would like to press forward, but before going farther one sees from the
                    example of others like oneself that this way is blocked. In such a case, if the
                    effort to push forward is not in harmony with the time, a reasonable and
                    resolute man will not expose himself to a personal rebuff, but will retreat
                    with others of like mind. This brings good fortune, because he does not
                    needlessly jeopardize himself.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    The spokes burst out of the wagon wheels.
                    Man and wife roll their eyes.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here an attempt is made to press forward forcibly, in the consciousness that
                    the obstructing power is slight. But since, under the circumstances, power
                    actually lies with the weak, this sudden offensive is doomed to failure.
                    External conditions hinder the advance, just as loss of the wheel spokes stops
                    the progress of a wagon. We do not yet heed this hint form fate, hence there
                    are annoying arguments like those of a married couple. Naturally this is not
                    a favorable state of thing, for though the situation may enable the weaker side
                    to hold its ground, the difficulties are too numerous to permit of a happy
                    result. In consequence even the strong man cannot so use his power as to
                    exert the right influence on those around him. He experiences a rebuff where
                    he expected an easy victory, and he thus compromises his dignity.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    If you are sincere, blood vanishes and fear gives way.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If one is in the difficult and responsible position of counselor to a powerful
                    man, on should restrain him in such a way that the threat of actual bloodshed
                    may arise. Nonetheless, the power of disinterested truth is greater than all
                    theses obstacles. It carries such weight that the end is achieved, and all danger
                    of bloodshed and all fear disappear.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    If you are sincere and loyally attached,
                    You are rich in your neighbor.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Loyalty leads to firm ties because it means that each partner complements the
                    other. In the weaker person loyalty consists in devotion, in the stronger it
                    consists in trustworthiness. This relation of mutual reinforcement leads to a
                    true wealth that is all the more apparent because it is not selfishly hoarded
                    but is shared with friends. Pleasure shared is pleasure doubled.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The rain comes, there is rest.
                    This is due to the lasting effect of character.
                    Perseverance brings the woman into danger.
                    The moon is nearly full.
                    If the superior man persists,
                    Misfortune comes.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Success is at hand. The wind has driven up the rain. A fixed standpoint has
                    been reach. This has come about through the cumulation of small effects
                    produced by reverence for a superior character. But a success thus secured bit
                    by bit calls for great caution. It would be a dangerous illusion for anyone to
                    think he could presume upon it. The female principle, the weak element
                    that has won the victory, should never persist in vaunting it— that would lead
                    to danger. The dark power in the moon is strongest when the moon is
                    almost full. When it is full and directly opposite the sun, its waning is
                    inevitable. Under such circumstances one must be content with what has
                    been achieved. To advance any further, before the appropriate time has
                    come, would lead to misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Treading (Conduct)" number="10">
        <description>
            The name of the hexagram means on the one hand the right way of
            conducting oneself. Heaven, the father, is above, and the lake, the youngest
            daughter, is below. This shows the difference between high and low, upon
            which composure correct social conduct, depends. On the other hand the
            word for the name of the hexagram, TREADING, means literally treading
            upon something. The small and cheerful [Tui] treads upon the large and
            strong [Ch'ien]. The direction of movement of the two primary trigrams is
            upward. The fact that the strong treads on the weak is not mentioned in the
            Book of Changes, because it is taken for granted. For the weak to take a stand
            against the strong is not dangerous here, because it happened in good humor
            [Tui] and without presumption, so that the strong man is not irritated but
            takes it all in good part.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                TREADING. Treading upon the tail of the tiger.
                It does not bite the man. Success.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The situation is really difficult. That which is strongest and that which is
                weakest are close together. The weak follows behind the strong and worries
                it. The strong, however, acquiesces and does not hurt the weak, because the
                contact is in goof humor and harmless.
                In terms of a human situation, one is handling wild, intractable people. In
                such a case one's purpose will be achieved if one behaves with decorum.
                Pleasant manners succeed even with irritable people.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven above, the lake below:
                The image of TREADING.
                Thus the superior man discriminates between high and low,
                And thereby fortifies the thinking of the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Heaven and the lake show a difference of elevation that inheres in the
                natures of the two, hence no envy arises. Among mankind also there are
                necessarily differences of elevation; it is impossible to bring about universal
                equality. But it is important that differences in social rank should not be
                arbitrary and unjust, for if this occurs, envy and class struggle are the
                inevitable consequences. If, on the other hand, external differences in rank
                correspond with differences in inner worth, and if inner worth forms the
                criterion of external rank, people acquiesce and order reigns in society.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Simple conduct. Progress without blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The situation is one in which we are still not bound by any obligations of
                    social intercourse. If our conduct is simple, we remain free of them We can
                    quietly follow our predilections as long as we are content and make not
                    demands on people.
                      The meaning of the hexagram is not standstill but progress. A man finds
                    himself in an altogether inferior position at the start. However, he has the
                    inner strength that guarantees progress. If he can be content with simplicity,
                    he can make progress without blame. When a man is dissatisfied with
                    modest circumstances, he is restless and ambitious and tries to advance, not
                    for the sake of accomplishing anything worth while, but merely in order to
                    escape from lowliness and poverty by dint of his conduct. Once his purpose is
                    achieved, he is certain to become arrogant and luxury-loving. Therefore
                    blame attaches to his progress. On the other hand, a man who is good at his
                    work is content to behave simply. He wishes to make progress in order to
                    accomplish something. When he attains his goal, he does something worth
                    while, an all is well.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Treading a smooth, level course.
                    The perseverance of a dark man
                    Brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The situation of a lonely sage is indicated here. He remains withdrawn from
                    the bustle of life, seeks nothing, asks nothing of anyone, and travels through
                    life unassailed, on a level road. Since he is content and does not challenge
                    fate, he remains free of entanglements.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    A one-eyed man is able to see,
                    A lame man is able to tread.
                    He treads on the tail of the tiger.
                    The tiger bites the man.
                    Misfortune.
                    Thus does a warrior act on behalf of his great prince.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A one-eyed man can indeed see, but not enough for clear vision. A lame
                    man can indeed treat, but not enough to make progress. If in spite of such
                    defects a man considers himself strong and consequently exposes himself to
                    danger, he is inviting disaster, for he is undertaking something beyond his
                    strength. This reckless way of plunging ahead, regardless of the adequacy of
                    one's powers, can be justified only in the case of a warrior battling for his
                    prince.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He treads on the tail of the tiger.
                    Caution and circumspection
                    Lead ultimately to good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This text refers to a dangerous enterprise. The inner power to carry it through
                    is there, but this inner power is combined with hesitating caution in one's
                    external attitude. This line contrasts with the preceding line, which is weak
                    within but outwardly presses forward. Here one is sure of ultimate success,
                    which consists in achieving one's purpose, that is, in overcoming danger by
                    going forward.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Resolute conduct.
                    Perseverance with awareness of danger.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to the ruler of the hexagram as a whole. One sees that one has to
                    be resolute in conduct. But at the same time one must remain conscious of
                    the danger connected with such resoluteness, especially if it is to be
                    persevered in. Only awareness of the danger makes success possible.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Look to your conduct and weigh the favorable signs.
                    When everything is fulfilled, supreme good fortune comes.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The work is ended. If we want to know whether good fortune will follow, we
                    must look back upon our conduct and its consequences. If the effects are good,
                    then good fortune is certain. No one knows himself. It is only by the
                    consequences of his actions, by the fruit of his labors, that a man can judge
                    what he is to expect.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Peace" number="11">
        <description>
            The Receptive, which moves downward, stands above; the Creative, which
            moves upward, is below. Hence their influences meet and are in harmony,
            so that all living things bloom and prosper. This hexagram belongs to the
            first month (February-March), at which time the forces of nature prepare the
            new spring.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                PEACE. The small departs,
                The great approaches.
                Good fortune. Success.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                This hexagram denotes a time in nature when heaven seems to be on earth.
                Heaven has placed itself beneath the earth, and so their powers unite in deep
                harmony. Then peace and blessing descend upon all living things.
                  In the world of man it is a time of social harmony; those in high places
                show favor to the lowly, and the lowly and inferior is an end to all feuds.
                  In side, at the center, in the key position, is the light principle; the dark
                principle is outside. Thus the light has a powerful influence, while the dark
                is submissive. In this way each receives its due. When the good elements of
                society occupy a central position and are in control, the evil elements come
                under their influence and change for the better. When the spirit of heaven
                rules in man, his animal nature also comes under its influence and takes its
                appropriate place.
                  The individual lines enter the hexagram from below and leave it again at
                the top. Here the small, weak, and evil elements are about to take their
                departure, while the great, strong, and good elements are moving up. This
                brings good fortune and success.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven and earth unite: the image of PEACE.
                Thus the ruler
                Divides and completes the course of heaven and earth,
                And so aids the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Heaven and earth are in contact and combine their influences, producing a
                time of universal flowering and prosperity. This stream of energy must be
                regulated by the ruler of men. It is done by a process of division. Thus men
                divide the uniform flow of time into the seasons, according to the succession
                of natural phenomena, and mark off infinite space by the points of the
                compass. In this way nature in its overwhelming profusion of phenomena is
                bounded and controlled. One the other hand, nature must be furthered in
                her productiveness. This is done by adjusting the products to the right time
                and the right place, which increases the natural yield.  This controlling and
                furthering activity of man in his relation to nature is the work on nature that
                rewards him.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    When ribbon grass is pulled up, the sod comes with it.
                    Each according to his kind.
                    Undertakings bring good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In times of prosperity every able man called to fill an office draws like minded
                    people along with him, just as in pulling up ribbon grass one always pulls up
                    a bunch of it, because the stalks are connected by their roots. In such times,
                    when it is possible to extend influence widely, the mind of an able man is set
                    upon going out into life and accomplishing something.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Bearing with the uncultured in gentleness,
                    Fording the river with resolution,
                    Not neglecting what is distant,
                    Not regarding one's companions:
                    Thus one may manage to walk in the middle.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In times of prosperity it is important and above all to possess enough
                    greatness of soul to bear with imperfect people. For in the hands of a great
                    master no material is unproductive; he can find use for everything. But this
                    generosity is by no means laxity or weakness. It is during times of prosperity
                    especially that we must always be ready to risk even dangerous undertakings,
                    such as the crossing of a river, if they are necessary. So too we must
                    not neglect what is distant but must attend scrupulously to everything.
                    Factionalism and the dominance of cliques are especially to be avoided.
                    Even if people of like mind come forward together, they ought not to form
                    a faction by holding together for mutual advantage; instead, each man
                    should do is duty. Theses are four ways in which one can overcome
                    the hidden danger of a gradual slackening that always lurks in any time
                    of peace. And that is how one finds the middle way for action.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    No plain not followed by a slope.
                    No going not followed by a return.
                    He who remains persevering in danger
                    Is without blame.
                    Do not complain about this truth;
                    Enjoy the good fortune you still possess.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Everything on earth is subject to change. Prosperity is followed by decline:
                    this is the eternal law on earth. Evil can indeed be held in check but not
                    permanently abolished. It always returns. This conviction might induct
                    melancholy, but it should not; it ought only to keep us from falling into
                    illusion when good fortune comes to us. If we continue mindful of the
                    danger, we remain persevering and make no mistakes. As long as a man's
                    inner nature remains stronger and richer than anything offered by external
                    fortune, as long as he remains inwardly superior to fate, fortune will not
                    desert him.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He flutters down, not boasting of his wealth,
                    Together with his neighbor,
                    Guileless and sincere.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In times of mutual confidence, people of high rank come in close contact with
                    the lowly quite simply and without boasting of their wealth. This is not due
                    to the force of circumstances but corresponds with their inmost sentiment.
                    The approach is made quite spontaneously, because it is based on inner
                    conviction.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    The sovereign I
                    Gives his daughter in marriage.
                    And supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The sovereign I is T'ang the Completer. By his decree the imperial princesses,
                    although higher in rank than their husbands, had to obey them like all other
                    wives. Here too we are shown a truly modest union of high and low that
                    brings happiness and blessings.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The wall falls back into the moat.
                    Use no army now.
                    Make your commands known within your own town.
                    Perseverance brings humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The change alluded to in the middle of the hexagram has begun to take place.
                    The wall of the town sinks back into the moat from which it was dug.
                    The hour of doom is at hand. When matters have come to this pass, we should
                    submit to fate and not try to stave it off by violent resistance. The one
                    recourse left us is to hold our own within our intimate circle. Should we
                    persevere in trying to resist the evil in the usual way, our collapse would
                    only be more complete, and humiliation would be the result.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Standstill (Stagnation)" number="12">
        <description>
            This hexagram is the opposite of the preceding one. Heaven is above, drawing
            farther and farther away, while the earth below sinks farther into the depths.
            The creative powers are not in relation. It is a time of standstill and
            decline. This hexagram is linked with the seventh month (August-September),
            when the year has passed its zenith and autumnal decay is setting in.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                STANDSTILL. Evil people do not further
                The perseverance of the superior man.
                The great departs; the small approaches.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Heaven and earth are out of communion and all things are benumbed. What is
                above has no relation to what is below, and on earth confusion and disorder
                prevail. The dark power is within, the light power is without. Weakness
                is within, harshness without. Within are the inferior, and without are
                the superior. The way of inferior people is in ascent; the way of superior
                people is one the decline. But the superior people do not allow themselves
                to be turned from their principles. If the possibility of exerting influence
                is closed to them, they nevertheless remain faithful to their principles and
                withdraw into seclusion.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven and earth do not unite:
                The image of STANDSTILL.
                Thus the superior man falls back upon his inner worth
                In order to escape the difficulties.
                He does not permit himself to be honored with revenue.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When, owing to the influence of inferior men, mutual mistrust prevails in
                public life, fruitful activity is rendered impossible, because the fundaments
                are wrong. Therefore the superior man knows what he must do under such
                circumstances; he does not allow himself to be tempted by dazzling offers
                to take part in public activities. This would only expose him to danger,
                since he cannot assent to the meanness of the others. He therefore hides
                his worth and withdraws into seclusion.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    When ribbon grass is pulled up, the sod comes with it.
                    Each according to his kind.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune and success.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The text is almost the same as that of the first line of the preceding hexagram,
                    but with a contrary meaning. In the latter a man is drawing another along with
                    him on the road to an official career; here a man is drawing another with him
                    into retirement form public life. This is why the text says here, "Perseverance
                    brings good fortune and success," and not "Undertakings bring good fortune."
                    If it becomes impossible to make our influence count, it is only by retirement
                    that we spare ourselves humiliation. Success in a higher sense can be ours,
                    because we know how to safeguard the value of our personalities.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    They bear and endure;
                    This means good fortune for inferior people.
                    The standstill serves to help the great man to attain success.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Inferior people are ready to flatter their superiors in a servile way.
                    They would also endure the superior man if he would put an end to their
                    confusion. This is fortunate for them. But the great man calmly bears
                    the consequences of the standstill. He does not mingle with the crowd
                    of the inferior; that is not his place. By his willingness to suffer
                    personally he insures the success of his fundamental principles.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    They bear shame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Inferior people who have risen to power illegitimately do not feel equal
                    to the responsibility they have taken upon themselves. In their hearts
                    they begin to be ashamed, although at first they do not show it outwardly.
                    This marks a turn for the better.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He who acts at the command of the highest
                    Remains without blame.
                    Those of like mind partake of the blessing.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The time of standstill is nearing the point of change into its opposite.
                    Whoever wishes to restore order must feel himself called to the task and
                    have the necessary authority. A man who sets himself up a capable of
                    creating order according to his own judgment could make mistakes and end
                    in failure. But the man who is truly called to the task is favored by the
                    conditions of the time, and all those of like mind will share in his blessing.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Standstill is giving way.
                    Good fortune for the great man.
                    "What if it should fail, what if it should fail?"
                    In this way he ties it to a cluster of mulberry shoots.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The time undergoes a change. The right man, able to restore order, has arrived.
                    Hence "good fortune." But such periods of transition are the very times in which
                    we must fear and tremble. Success is assured only through greatest caution,
                    which asks always, "What if it should fail?" When a mulberry bush is cut down,
                    a number of unusually strong shoots sprout from the roots. Hence the image of
                    tying something to a cluster of mulberry shoots is used to symbolize the way
                    of making success certain. Confucius says about this line:

                    Danger arises when a man feels secure in his position. Destruction threatens
                    when a man seeks to preserve his worldly estate. Confusion develops when a
                    man has put everything in order. Therefore the superior man does not forget
                    danger in his security, not ruin when he is well established, nor confusion
                    when his affairs are in order. In this way he gains personal safety and is
                    able to protect the empire.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The standstill comes to an end.
                    First standstill, then good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The standstill does not last forever. However, it does not cease of its own accord;
                    the right man is needed to end it. This is the difference between a state of peace
                    and a state of stagnation. Continuous effort is necessary to maintain peace:
                    left to itself it would change into stagnation and disintegration. The time
                    of disintegration, however, does not change back automatically to a condition
                    of peace and prosperity; effort must be put forth in order to end it. This shows
                    the creative attitude that man must take if the world is to be put in order.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Fellowship with Men" number="13">
        <description>
            The image of the upper trigram Ch'ien is heaven, and that of the lower, Li, is flame.
            It is the nature of fire to flame up to the heaven. This gives the idea of fellowship.
            IT is the second line that, by virtue of its central character, unites the five strong
            lines around it. This hexagram forms a complement to Shih, THE ARMY (7).
            In the latter, danger is within and obedience without— the character of a warlike army,
            which, in order to hold together, needs one strong man among the many who are weak. Here,
            clarity is within and strength without— the character of a peaceful union of men,
            which, in order to hold together, needs one yielding nature among many firm persons.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                FELLOWSHIP WITH MEN in the open.
                Success.
                It furthers one to cross the great water.
                The perseverance of the superior man furthers.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                True fellowship among men must be based upon a concern that is universal.
                It is not the private interests of the individual that create lasting fellowship
                among men, but rather the goals of humanity. That is why it is said that fellowship
                with men in the open succeeds. If unity of this kind prevails, even difficult and
                dangerous tasks, such as crossing the great water, can be accomplished. But in order
                to bring about this sort of fellowship, a persevering and enlightened leader is needed—
                a man with clear, convincing, and inspiring aims and the strength to carry them out.
                (The inner trigram means clarity; the outer, strength.)
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven together with fire:
                The image of FELLOWSHIP WITH MEN.
                Thus the superior man organizes the clans
                And makes distinctions between things.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Heaven has the same direction of movement as fire, yet it is different from
                fire. Just as the luminaries in the sky serve for the systematic division and
                arrangement of time, so human society and all things that really belong
                together must be organically arranged. Fellowship should not be a mere
                mingling of individuals or of things— that would be chaos, not fellowship.
                If fellowship is to lead to order, there must be organization within diversity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Fellowship with men at the gate.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The beginning of union among people should take place before the door.
                    All are equally close to one another. No divergent aims have yet arisen,
                    and one makes not mistakes. The basic principles of any kind of union must
                    be equally accessible to all concerned. Secret agreements bring misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Fellowship with men in the clan.
                    Humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    There is danger here of formation of a separate faction on the basis of
                    personal and egotistic interests. Such factions, which are exclusive and,
                    instead of welcoming all men, must condemn one group in order to unite the
                    others, originate from low motives and therefore lead in the course of time
                    to humiliation.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    He hides weapons in the thicket;
                    He climbs the high hill in front of it.
                    For three years he does not rise up.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here fellowship has changed about to mistrust. Each man distrusts the other,
                    plans a secret ambush, and seeks to spy on his fellow form afar. We are
                    dealing with an obstinate opponent whom we cannot come at by this method.
                    Obstacles standing in the way of fellowship with others are shown here. One
                    has mental reservations for one's own part and seeks to take his opponent by
                    surprise. This very fact makes one mistrustful, suspecting the same wiles in
                    his opponent and trying to ferret them out. The result is that one departs
                    further and further from true fellowship. The longer this goes on, the more
                    alienated one becomes.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He climbs up on his wall; he cannot attack.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the reconciliation that follows quarrel mover nearer. It is true that there
                    are still dividing walls on which we stand confronting one another. But the
                    difficulties are too great. We get into straits, and this brings us to our senses.
                    We cannot fight, and therein lies our good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Men bound in fellowship first weep and lament,
                    But afterward they laugh.
                    After great struggles they succeed in meeting.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Two people are outwardly separated, but in their hearts they are united. They
                    are kept apart by their positions in life. Many difficulties and obstructions
                    arise between them and cause them grief. But, remaining true to each other,
                    the allow nothing to separate them, and although it costs them a severe
                    struggle to overcome the obstacles, they will succeed. When they come
                    together their sadness will change to joy. Confucius says of this:

                    Life leads the thoughtful man on a path of many windings.
                    Now the course is checked, now it runs straight again.
                    Here winged thoughts may pour freely forth in words,
                    There the heavy burden of knowledge must be shut away in silence.
                    But when two people are at one in the inmost hearts,
                    They shatter even the strength of iron or of bronze.
                    And when two people understand each other in their inmost hearts,
                    Their words are sweet and strong, like the fragrance of orchids.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Fellowship with men in the meadow.
                    No remorse.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The warm attachment that springs from the heart is lacking here. We are by
                    this time actually outside of fellowship with others. However, we ally
                    ourselves with them. The fellowship does not include all, but only those
                    who happen to dwell near one another. The meadow is the pasture at the
                    entrance to the town. At this stage, the ultimate goal of the union of
                    mankind has not yet been attained, but we need not reproach ourselves.
                    We join the community without separate aims of our own.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Possession in Great Measure" number="14">
        <description>
            The fire in heaven above shines far, and all things stand out in the light and
            become manifest. The weak fifth line occupies the place of honor and all the
            strong lines are in accord with it. All things come to the man who is modest
            and kind in a high position.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                POSSESSION IN GREAT MEASURE.
                Supreme success.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The two trigrams indicate that strength and clarity unite. Possessions great
                measure is determined by fate and accords with the time. How is it possible
                that the weak line has power to hold the strong lines fast and to possess
                them? It is done by virtue of unselfish modesty. The time is favorable—
                a time of strength within, clarity and culture without. Power is expressing
                itself in graceful and controlled way. This brings supreme success and wealth.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Fire in heaven above:
                The image of POSSESSION IN GREAT MEASURE.
                Thus the superior man curbs evil and furthers good,
                And thereby obeys the benevolent will of heaven.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The sun in heaven above, shedding light over everything one earth, is the
                image of possession on a grand scale. But a possession of this sort must be
                administered properly. The sun brings both evil and good into the light of
                day. Man must combat and curb the evil, and must favor and promote the
                good. Only in this way does he fulfill the benevolent will of God,
                who desires only good and not evil.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    No relationship with what is harmful;
                    There is no blame in this.
                    If one remains conscious of difficulty,
                    One remains without blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Great possession that is still in its beginnings and that has not yet been
                    challenged brings no blame, since there has been no opportunity to make
                    mistakes. Yet there are many difficulties to be overcome. It is only by
                    remaining conscious of theses difficulties that one can keep inwardly free of
                    possible arrogance and wastefulness, and thus in principle overcome all cause
                    for blame.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    A big wagon for loading.
                    One may undertake something.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Great possession consists not only in the quantity of goods at one's disposal,
                    but first and foremost, in their mobility and utility, for then they can be
                    used in undertakings, and we remain free of embarrassment and mistakes.
                    The big wagon, which will carry a heavy load and in which one can journey
                    farm means that there are at hand able helpers who give their support and
                    are equal to their task. One can load great responsibility upon such persons,
                    and this is necessary in important undertakings.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    A prince offers it to the Son of Heaven.
                    A petty man cannot do this.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A magnanimous, liberal-minded man should not regard what he possesses as his
                    exclusive personal property , but should place it at the disposal of the ruler
                    or of the people at large. In so doing, he takes the right attitude toward
                    his possession, which as private property can never endure. A petty man is
                    incapable of this. He is harmed by great possessions, because instead of
                    sacrificing them, he would keep them for himself.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He makes a difference
                    Between himself and his neighbor.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This characterizes the position of a man placed among rich and powerful
                    neighbors. It is a dangerous position. He must look neither to the right nor
                    to the left, and must shun envy and the temptation to vie with others. In this
                    way he remains free of mistakes.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    He whose truth is accessible, yet dignified,
                    Has good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The situation is very favorable. People are being won not by coercion but by
                    unaffected sincerity, so that they are attached to us in sincerity and truth.
                    However, benevolence alone is not sufficient at the time of POSSESSION IN
                    GREAT MEASURE. For insolence might begin to spread. Insolence must be
                    kept in bounds by dignity; then good fortune is assured.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    He is blessed by heaven.
                    Good fortune.
                    Nothing that does not further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In the fullness of possession and at the height of power, one remains modest
                    and gives honor to the sage who stands outside the affairs of the world. By
                    this means one puts oneself under the beneficent influence descending form
                    heaven, and all goes well. Confucius says of this line:

                    To bless means to help. Heaven helps the man who is devoted; men help the
                    man who is true. He who walks in truth and is devoted in his thinking, and
                    furthermore reveres the worthy, is blessed by heaven. He has good fortune,
                    and there is nothing that would not further.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Modesty" number="15">
        <description>
            This hexagram is made up of the trigrams Kên, Keeping Still, mountain,
            and K'un. The mountain is the youngest son of the Creative, the representative
            of heaven and earth. It dispenses the blessings of heaven, the clouds and rain
            that gather round its summit, and thereafter shines forth radiant with
            heavenly light. This shows what modesty is and how it functions in great
            and strong men. K'un, the earth, stands above. Lowliness is a quality of the
            earth: this is the very reason why it appears in this hexagram as exalted,
            by being placed above the mountain. This shows how modesty functions in
            lowly, simple people: they are lifted up by it.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                MODESTY creates success.
                The superior man carries things through.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                It is the law of heaven to make fullness empty and to make full what is
                modest; when the sun is at its zenith, it must, according to the law of heaven,
                turn toward its setting, and at its nadir it rises toward a new dawn. In
                obedience to the same law, the moon when it is full begins to wane, and
                when empty of light it waxes again. This heavenly law works itself out
                in the fates of men also. It is the law of earth to alter the full and
                to contribute to the modest. High mountains are worn down by the waters,
                and the valleys are filled up. It is the law of fate to undermine what is full
                and to prosper the modest. And men also hate fullness and love the modest.
                  The destinies of men are subject to immutable laws that must fulfill
                themselves. But man has it in his power to shape his fate, according as his
                behavior exposes him to the influence of benevolent or of destructive forces.
                When a man holds a high position and is nevertheless modest, he shines
                with the light of wisdom; if he is in a lowly position and is modest, he cannot
                be passed by. Thus the superior man can carry out his work to the end
                without boasting of what he has achieved.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Within the earth, a mountain:
                The image of MODESTY.
                Thus the superior man reduces that which is too much,
                And augments that which is too little.
                He weighs things and makes them equal.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The wealth of the earth in which a mountain is hidden is not visible to the
                eye, because the depths are offset by the height of the mountain. Thus high
                and low competent each other and the result is the plain. Here an effect
                that it took a long time to achieve, but that in the end seems easy of
                accomplishment and self-evident, is used as the image of modesty. The
                superior man does the same thing when he establishes order in the world; he
                equalizes the extremes that are the source of social discontent and thereby
                creates just and equable conditions.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    A superior man modest about his modesty
                    May cross the great water.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A dangerous enterprise, such as the crossing of a great stream, is made much
                    more difficult if many claims and considerations have to be taken into
                    account. On the other hand, the task is easy if it is attended to quickly and
                    simply. Therefore the unassuming attitude of mind that goes with modesty
                    fits a man to accomplish even difficult undertakings: he imposes no
                    demands or stipulations but settles matters easily and quickly. Where no
                    claims are put forward, no resistances arise.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Modesty that comes to expression. Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    "Out of the fullness of the heart the mouth speaketh." When a man's
                    attitude of mind is so modest that this expresses itself in his outward
                    behavior, it is a source of good fortune to him. For the possibility of
                    exerting a lasting influence arises of itself and no one can interfere.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    A superior man of modesty and merit
                    Carries things to conclusion.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This is the center of the hexagram, where its secret is disclosed. A
                    distinguished name is readily earned by great achievements. If a man allows
                    himself to be dazzled by fame, he will soon be criticized, and difficulties
                    will arise. If, on the contrary, he remains modest despite his merit,
                    he makes himself beloved and wins the support necessary for carrying
                    his work through to the end.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Nothing that would not further modesty
                    In movement.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Everything has its proper measure. Even modesty in behavior can be carried
                    too far. Here, however, it is appropriate, because the place between a worthy
                    helper below and a kindly ruler above carries great responsibility. The
                    confidence of the man in superior place must not be abused nor the merits of
                    the man in inferior placed concealed. There are officials who indeed do not
                    strive for prominence; they hide behind the letter of ordinances, decline all
                    responsibility, accept pay without giving its equivalent in work, and bear
                    empty titles. This is the opposite of what is meant here by modesty. In such
                    a position, modesty is shown by interest in one's work.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    No boasting of wealth before one's neighbor.
                    It is favorable to attack with force.
                    Nothing that would not further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Modesty is not to be confused with weak good nature that lets things take
                    their own course. When a man holds a responsible position, he must at times
                    resort to energetic measures. In doing so he must not try to make an
                    impression by boasting of his superiority but must make certain of the people
                    around him. The measures taken should be purely objective and in no way
                    personally offensive. Thus modesty manifests itself even in severity.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Modesty that comes to expression.
                    It is favorable to set armies marching
                    To chastise one's own city and one's country.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A person who is really sincere in his modesty must make it show in reality.
                    He must proceed with great energy in this. When enmity arises nothing is
                    easier than to lay the blame on another. A weak man takes offense perhaps,
                    and draws back, feeling self-pity; he thinks that it is modesty that keeps
                    him from defending himself. Genuine modesty sets one to creating order and
                    inspires one to begin by disciplining one's own ego and one's immediate
                    circle. Only through having the courage to marshal one's armies against
                    oneself, will something forceful really be achieved.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="Enthusiasm" number="16">
        <description>
            The strong line in the fourth place, that of the leading official, meets
            with response and obedience from all the other lines, which are all weak.
            The attribute of the upper trigram, Chên, is movement; the attributes
            of K'un, the lower, are obedience and devotion. This begins a movement
            that meets with devotion and therefore inspires enthusiasm, carrying all
            with it. Of great importance, furthermore, is the law of movement along
            the line of least resistance, which in this hexagram is enunciated as
            the law for natural events and for human life.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                ENTHUSIASM. It furthers one to install helpers
                And to set armies marching.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The time of ENTHUSIASM derives from the fact that there is at hand an
                eminent man who is in sympathy with the spirit of the people and acts
                in accord with it. Hence he finds universal and willing obedience.
                To arouse enthusiasm it is necessary for a man to adjust himself
                and his ordinances to the character of those whom he has to lead.
                The inviolability of natural laws rests on this principle of movement
                along the line of least resistance. Theses laws are not forces external
                to things but represent the harmony of movement immanent in them. That
                is why the celestial bodies do not deviate from their orbits and why
                all events in nature occur with fixed regularity. It is the same with
                human society: only such laws are rooted in popular sentiment can be
                enforced, while laws violating this sentiment merely arouse resentment.
                   Again, it is enthusiasm that enables us to install helpers for
                the completion of an undertaking without fear of secret opposition.
                It is enthusiasm too that can unify mass movements, as in war,
                so that they achieve victory.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Thunder comes resounding out of the earth:
                The image of ENTHUSIASM.
                Thus the ancient kings made music
                In order to honor merit,
                And offered it with splendor
                To the Supreme Deity,
                Inviting their ancestors to be present.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When, at the beginning of summer, thunder— electrical energy—
                comes rushing forth from the earth again, and the first thunderstorm
                refreshes nature, a prolonged state of tension is resolved. Joy and
                relief make themselves felt. So too, music has power to ease tension
                within the heart and to loosen the grip of obscure emotions. The
                enthusiasm of the heart expresses itself involuntarily in a burst
                of song, in dance and rhythmic movement of the body. From immemorial
                times the inspiring effect of the invisible sound that moves all
                hearts, and draws them together, has mystified mankind.
                  Rulers have made use of this natural taste for music; they elevated
                and regulated it. Music was looked upon as something serious and holy,
                designed to purify the feelings of men. It fell to music to glorify
                the virtues of heroes and thus to construct a bridge to the world
                of the unseen. In the temple men drew near to God with music and
                pantomimes (out of this later the theater developed). Religious
                feeling for the Creator of the world was united with the most
                sacred of human feelings, that of reverence for the ancestors.
                The ancestors were invited to these divine services as guests
                of the Ruler of Heaven and as representatives of humanity in
                the higher regions. This uniting of the human past with the
                Divinity in solemn moments of religious inspiration established
                the bond between God and man. The ruler who revered the Divinity
                in revering his ancestors became thereby the Son of Heaven, in
                whom the heavenly and the earthly world met in mystical contact.
                  These ideas are the final summation of Chinese culture. Confucius
                has said of the great sacrifice at which these rites were performed:
                "He who could wholly comprehend this sacrifice could rule the world
                as though it were spinning on his hand."
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Enthusiasm that expresses itself
                    Brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man in an inferior position has aristocratic connections about which
                    he boasts enthusiastically. This arrogance inevitably invites misfortune.
                    Enthusiasm should never be an egotistic emotion; it is justified only
                    when it is a general feeling that unites one with others.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Firm as a rock. Not a whole day.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This describes a person who does not allow himself to be misled by any
                    illusions. While others are letting themselves be dazzled by enthusiasm,
                    he recognizes with perfect clarity the first signs of the time. Thus he
                    neither flatters those above nor neglects those beneath him; he is as firm
                    as a rock. When the first sign of discord appears, he knows the right moment
                    for withdrawing and does not delay even for a day. Perseverance in such
                    conduct will bring good fortune. Confucius says about this line:

                    To know the seeds, that is divine indeed. In his association with those
                    above him, the superior man does not flatter. In his association with
                    those beneath him, he is not arrogant. For he knows the seeds. The seeds
                    are the first imperceptible beginning of movement, the first trace of
                    good fortune (or misfortune) that shows itself. The superior man perceives
                    the seeds and immediately takes actin. He does not wait even a whole day.
                    In the Book of Changes it is said: "Firm as a rock. Not a whole day.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune."

                    Firm as a rock, what need of a whole day?
                    The judgment can be known.
                    The superior man knows what is hidden and what is evident.
                    He knows weakness, he knows strength as well.
                    Hence the myriads look up to him.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Six in the third place means:
                    Enthusiasm that looks upward creates remorse.
                    Hesitation brings remorse.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This line is the opposite of the preceding one: the latter bespeaks
                    self-reliance, while here there is enthusiastic looking up to a leader.
                    If a man hesitates too long, this also will bring remorse. The right
                    moment for approach must be seized: only then will he do the right thing.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The source of enthusiasm.
                    He achieves great things.
                    Doubt not.
                    You gather friends around you
                    As a hair clasp gathers the hair.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This describes a man who is able to awaken enthusiasm through his own
                    sureness and freedom from hesitation. He attracts people because he has no
                    doubts and is wholly sincere. Owing to his confidence in them he wins their
                    enthusiastic co-operation and attains success. Just as a clasp draws the hair
                    together and hold it, so he draws man together by the support he gives them.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Persistently ill, and still does not die.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here enthusiasm is obstructed. A man is under constant pressure,
                    which prevents him from breathing freely. However, this pressure has
                    its advantage— it prevents him from consuming his powers in empty
                    enthusiasm. Thus constant pressure can actually serve to keep one alive.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Deluded enthusiasm.
                    But if after completion one changes,
                    There is no blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It is a bad thing for a man to let himself be deluded by enthusiasm. But if this
                    delusion has run its course, and he is still capable of changing, then he is
                    freed of error. A sober awakening from false enthusiasm is quite possible and
                    very favorable.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Following" number="17">
        <description>
            The trigram Tui, the Joyous, whose attribute is gladness, is above; Chên, the
            Arousing, which has the attribute of movement, is below. Joy in movement
            induces following. The Joyous is the youngest daughter, while the Arousing
            is the eldest son. An older man defers to a young girl and shows her
            consideration. By this he moves her to follow him.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                FOLLOWING has supreme success.
                Perseverance furthers. No blame.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In order to obtain a following one must first know how to adapt oneself. If a
                man would rule he must first learn to serve, for only in this way does he
                secure from those below him the joyous assent that is necessary if they are to
                follow him. If he has to obtain a following by force or cunning, by conspiracy
                or by creating faction, he invariably arouses resistance, which obstructs
                willing adherence. But even joyous movement can lead to evil
                consequences, hence the added stipulation, "Perseverance furthers" — that is,
                consistency in doing right—  together with "No blame." Just as we should not
                ask others to follow us unless this condition is fulfilled, so it is only under
                this condition that we can in turn follow others without coming to harm.
                  The thought of obtaining a following through adaptation to the demands of
                the time is a great and significant idea; this is why the appended judgment is
                so favorable.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Thunder in the middle of the lake:
                The image of FOLLOWING.
                Thus the superior man at nightfall
                Goes indoors for rest and recuperation.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In the autumn electricity withdraws into the earth again and rests. Here it is
                the thunder in the middle of the lake that serves as the image— thunder in its
                winter rest, not thunder in motion. The idea of following in the sense of
                adaptation to the demands of the time grows out of this image. Thunder in
                the middle of the lake indicates times of darkness and rest. Similarly, a
                superior man, after being tirelessly active all day, allows himself rest and
                recuperation at night. No situation can become favorable until one is able to
                adapt to it and does not wear himself out with mistaken resistance.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    The standard is changing.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                    To go out of the door in company
                    Produces deeds.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    There are exceptional conditions in which the relation between leader and
                    followers changes. It is implicit in the idea of following and adaptation that if
                    one wants to lead others, one must remain accessible and responsive to the
                    views of those under him. At the same time, however, he must have firm
                    principles, so that he does not vacillate where there is only a question of
                    current opinion. Once we are ready to listen to the opinions of others, we
                    must not associate exclusively with people who share our views or with
                    members of our own party; instead, we must go out and mingle freely with
                    all sorts of people, friends or foes. That is the only way to achieve something.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    If one clings to the little boy,
                    One loses the strong man.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In friendships and close relationships an individual must make a careful
                    choice. He surrounds himself either with good or with bad company; he
                    cannot have both at once. If he throws himself away on unworthy friends he
                    loses connection with people of intellectual power who could further him in
                    the good.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    If one clings to the strong man,
                    One loses the little boy.
                    Through following one finds what one seeks.
                    It furthers one to remain persevering.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When the right connection with distinguished people has been found, a
                    certain loss naturally ensues. A man must part company with the inferior
                    and superficial. But in his heart he will feel satisfied, because he seeks and
                    needs for the development of his personality. The important thing is to
                    remain firm. He must know what he wants and not be led astray by
                    momentary inclinations.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Following creates success.
                    Perseverance brings misfortune.
                    To go one's way with sincerity brings clarity.
                    How could there be blame in this?
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It often happens, when a man exerts a certain amount of influence, that he
                    obtains a following by condescension toward inferiors. But the people who
                    attach themselves to him are not honest in their intentions. They seek
                    personal advantage and try to make themselves indispensable through
                    flattery and subservience. If one becomes accustomed to such satellites and
                    cannot do without them, it brings misfortune. Only when a man is
                    completely free from his ego, and intent, by conviction, upon what is right
                    and essential, does he acquire the clarity that enables him to see through such
                    people, and become free of blame.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Sincere in the good. Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Every man must have something he follows— something that serves him as a
                    lodestar. He who follows with conviction the beautiful and the good may feel
                    himself strengthened by this saying.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    He meets with firm allegiance
                    And is still further bound.
                    The king introduces him
                    To the Western Mountain.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to a man, an exalted sage, who has already put the turmoil of the
                    world behind him. But a follower appears who understands him and is not
                    to be put off. So the sage comes back into the world and aids the other in his
                    work. Thus there develops an eternal tie between the two.
                      The allegory is chosen from the annals of the Chou dynasty. The rulers of
                    this dynasty honored men who had served them well by awarding them a
                    place in the royal family's temple of ancestors on the Western Mountain. In
                    this way they were regarded as sharing in the destiny of the ruling family.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Work on what has been spoiled (Decay)" number="18">
        <description>
            The Chinese character ku represents a bowl in whose contents worms are
            breeding. This means decay. IT is come about because the gentle indifference
            in the lower trigram has come together with the rigid inertia of the upper,
            and the result is stagnation. Since this implies guilt, the conditions embody a
            demand for removal of the cause. Hence the meaning of the hexagram is not
            simply "what has been spoiled" but "work on what has been spoiled".
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                WORK ON WHAT HAS BEEN SPOILED
                Has supreme success.
                It furthers one to cross the great water.
                Before the starting point, three days.
                After the starting point, three days.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                What has been spoiled through man's fault can be made good again through
                man's work. IT is not immutable fate, as in the time of STANDSTILL, that
                has caused the state of corruption, but rather the abuse of human freedom.
                Work toward improving conditions promises well, because it accords the
                possibilities of the time. We must not recoil from work and danger-
                symbolized by crossing of the great water-but must take hold energetically.
                Success depends, however, on proper deliberation. This is expressed by the
                lines, "Before the starting point, three days. After the starting point, three
                days." We must first know the cause of corruption before we can do away
                with them; hence it is necessary to be cautious during the time before the
                start. Then we must see to it that the new way is safely entered upon, so that
                a relapse may be avoided; therefore we must pay attention to the time after
                the start. Decisiveness and energy must take the place of inertia and
                indifference that have led to decay, in order that the ending may be followed
                by a new beginning.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The wind blows low on the mountain:
                The image of DECAY.
                Thus the superior man stirs up the people
                And strengthens their spirit.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When the wind blow s slow on the mountain, it is thrown back and spoils
                the vegetation. This contains a challenge to improvement. It is the same
                with debasing attitudes and fashions; they corrupt human society. His
                methods likewise must be derived from the two trigrams, but in such a way
                that their effects unfold in orderly sequence. The superior must first remove
                stagnation by stirring up public opinion, as the wind stirs up everything, and
                must strengthen and tranquilize the character of the people, as the mountain
                gives tranquillity and nourishment to all that grows in its vicinity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Setting right what has been spoiled by the father.
                    If there is a son,
                    No blame rests upon the departed father.
                    Danger. In the end good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Rigid adherence to tradition has resulted in decay. But the decay has not yet
                    penetrated deeply and so can still be easily remedied. It is as if a son were
                    compensated for the decay his father allowed to creep in. Then no blame
                    attaches to the father. However, one must not overlook the danger or take
                    the matter too lightly. Only if one is conscious of the danger connected with
                    every reform will everything go well in the end.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Setting right what has been spoiled by the mother.
                    One must not be too persevering.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This refers to mistakes that as a result of weakness have brought about decay-
                    hence the symbol, "what has been spoiled by the mother. " In setting things
                    right in such a case, a certain gentle consideration is called for. In order not to
                    wound, one should not attempt to proceed too drastically.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Setting right what has been spoiled by the father.
                    There will be a little remorse. No great blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This describes a man who proceeds a little too energetically in righting the
                    mistakes of the past. Now and then, as a result, minor discourse and
                    annoyances will surely develop. But too much energy is better than too little.
                    Therefore, although he may at times have slight cause for regret, he remains
                    free of any serious blame.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Tolerating what has been spoiled by the father.
                    In continuing one sees humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This shows the situation of someone too weak to take measures against decay
                    that has its roots in the past and is just beginning to manifest itself. It is
                    allowed to run its course. If this continues, humiliation will result.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Setting right what has been spoiled by the father.
                    One meets with praise.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An individual is confronted with corruption originating from neglect in
                    former times. He lacks the power to ward it off alone, but with able helpers
                    he can at least bring about a thorough reform, if he cannot create a new
                    beginning, and this also is praiseworthy.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    He does not serve kings and princes,
                    Sets himself higher goals.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Not every man has an obligation to mingle in the affairs of the world. There
                    are some who are developed to such a degree that they are justified in letting
                    the world go its own way and refusing to enter public life with a view to
                    reforming it. But this does not imply a right to remain idle or to sit back and
                    merely criticize. Such withdrawal is justified only when we strive to realize
                    in ourselves the higher aims of mankind. For although the sage remains
                    distant from the turmoil of daily life, he creates incomparable human values
                    for the future.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Approach" number="19">
        <description>
            The Chinese word lin has a range of meanings that is not exhausted by any
            single word of another language. The ancient explanations in the Book of
            Changes give as its first meaning, "becoming great." What becomes great are
            the two strong lines growing into the hexagram from below; the light-giving
            power expands with them. The meaning is then further extended to include
            the concept of approach, especially the approach of what is lower. Finally the
            meaning includes the attitude of condescension of a man in high position
            toward the people, and in general the setting to work on affairs. This
            hexagram is linked with the twelfth month (January-February), when after
            the winter solstice, the light power begins to ascend again.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                APPROACH has supreme success.
                Perseverance furthers.
                When the eighth month comes,
                There will be misfortune.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The hexagram as a whole points to a time of joyous, hopeful progress. Spring
                is approaching. Joy and forbearance bring high and low nearer together.
                Success is certain. But we must work with determination and perseverance
                to make full use of the propitiousness of the time. And on thing more:
                spring does not last forever. In the eighth month the aspects are reversed.
                Then only two strong, light lines are left; these do not advance but are in
                retreat (see next hexagram). We must take heed of this change in good time.
                If we meet evil before it becomes reality-before it has even begun to stir-we
                can master it.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The earth above the lake:
                The image of APPROACH.
                Thus the superior man is inexhaustible
                In his will to teach,
                And without limits
                In his tolerance and protection of the people.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The earth borders upon the lake from above. This symbolizes the approach
                and condescension of the man of higher position to those beneath him. The
                two parts of the image indicate what his attitude toward these people will be.
                Just as the lake is inexhaustible in depth, so the sage is inexhaustible in his
                readiness to teach mankind, and just as the earth is boundlessly wide,
                sustaining and caring for all creatures on it, so the sage sustains and cares for
                all people and excludes no part of humanity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Joint approach.
                    Perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The good begins to prevail and to find response in influential circles. This in
                    turn is an incentive to men of ability. IT is well to join this upward trend, but
                    we must not let ourselves be carried away by the current of the time; we must
                    adhere perseveringly to what is right. This bring good fortune.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Joint approach.
                    Good fortune.
                    Everything furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When the stimulus to approach comes from a high place, and when a man
                    has the inner strength and consistency that need no admonition, good
                    fortune will ensue. Nor need the future cause any concern. He is well aware
                    that everything earthly is transitory, and that a descent follows upon every
                    rise, but need not be confused by this universal law of fate. Everything serves
                    to further. Therefore he will travel the paths of life swiftly, honestly, and
                    valiantly.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Comfortable approach.
                    Nothing that would further.
                    If one is induced to grieve over it,
                    One becomes free of blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Things are going well for a man: he achieves power and influence. But in
                    this lies the danger that he may relax, and confident of his position, allow the
                    easygoing, careless mood to show itself in his dealings with other people.
                    This would inevitably be harmful. But there is possibility of a change of
                    mood. If he regrets his mistaken attitude and feels the responsibility of an
                    influential position, he frees himself of faults.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Complete approach.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    While the three lower lines indicate rise to power and influence, the three
                    upper lines show the attitude of persons in higher position toward those of
                    lower rank for whom they procure influence. Here is shown the open-
                    minded approach of a person of high rank to a man of ability whom he draws
                    in to his own circle, regardless of class prejudice. This is very favorable.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Wise approach.
                    This is right for a great prince.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A prince, or anyone in a leading position, must have the wisdom to attract to
                    himself people of ability who are expert in directing affairs. His wisdom
                    consists both in selecting the right people and in allowing those chosen to
                    have a free hand without interference from him.  For only through such self-
                    restraint will he find the experts needed to satisfy all of his requirements.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Great hearted approach.
                    Good-hearted approach.
                    Good fortune. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A sage who has put the world behind him and who in spirit has already
                    withdrawn from life may, under certain circumstances, decide to return once
                    more to the here and now and to approach other men. This means great
                    good fortune for the men whom he teaches and helps. And for him this great
                    hearted humbling of himself is blameless.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Contemplation (View)" number="20">
        <description>
            A slight variation of tonal stress gives the Chinese name for this hexagram a
            double meaning.  It means both contemplating and being seen, in the sense
            of being an example. These ideas are suggested by the fact that the hexagram
            can be understood as picturing a type of tower characteristic of ancient China.


            A tower of this kind commanded a wide view of the country; at the same
            time, when situated on a mountain, it became a landmark that could be seen
            for miles around. Thus the hexagram shows a ruler who contemplates the
            law of heaven above him and the ways of the people below, and who, by
            means of good government, sets a lofty example to the masses.
              This hexagram is linked with the eight month (September-October). The
            light-giving power retreats and the dark power is again on the increase.
            However, this aspect is not material in the interpretation of the hexagram as a
            whole.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                CONTEMPLATION. The ablution has been made,
                But not yet the offering.
                Full of trust they look up to him.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The sacrificial ritual in China began with an ablution and a libation by which
                the Deity was invoked, after which the sacrifice was offered. The moment of
                time between these two ceremonies is the most sacred of all, the moment of
                deepest inner concentration. If piety is sincere and expressive of real faith, the
                contemplation of it has a transforming awe-spiring effect on those who
                witness it.
                  Thus also in nature a holy seriousness is to be seen in the fact that natural
                occurrences are uniformly subject to law. Contemplation of the divine
                meaning underlying the workings of the universe gives to the man who is
                called upon to influence others the means of producing like effects. This
                requires that power of inner concentration which religious contemplation
                develops in great men strong in faith. It enables them to apprehend the
                mysterious and divine laws of life, and by means of profoundest inner
                concentration they give expression to these laws in their own persons. Thus
                a hidden spiritual power emanates from them, influencing and dominating
                others without their being aware of how it happens.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The wind blows over the earth:
                The image of CONTEMPLATION.
                Thus the kings of old visited the regions of the world,
                Contemplated the people,
                And gave them instruction.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When the wind blows over the earth it goes far and wide, and the grass must
                bend to its power. These two occurrences find confirmation in the hexagram.
                The two images are used to symbolize a practice of the kings of old; in making
                regular journeys the ruler could, in the first place, survey his realm and make
                certain that none of the existing usages of the people escaped notice; in the
                second, he could exert influence through which such customs as were
                unsuitable could be changed.
                  All of this points to the power possessed by a superior personality. On the
                one hand, such a man will have a view of the real sentiments of the great
                mass of humanity and therefore cannot be deceived; on the other, he will
                impress the people so profoundly, by his mere existence and by the impact of
                his personality, that they will be swayed by him as the grass by the wind.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Boy like contemplation.
                    For an inferior man, no blame.
                    For a superior man, humiliation.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This means contemplation from a distance, without comprehension. A man
                    of influence is at hand, abut his influence is not understood by the common
                    people. This matters little in the case of the masses, for they benefit by the
                    actions of the ruling sage whether they understand them or not. But for a
                    superior man it is a disgrace. He must not content himself with a shallow,
                    thoughtless view of prevailing forces; he must contemplate them as a
                    connected whole and try to understand them.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Contemplation through the crack of the door.
                    Furthering for the perseverance of a woman.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Through the crack of the door one has a limited outlook; one looks outward
                    from within. Contemplation is subjectively limited. One tends to relate
                    everything to oneself and cannot put oneself in another's place and
                    understand his motives. This is appropriate for a good housewife. It is not
                    necessary for her to be conversant with the affairs of the world. But for a man
                    who must take active part in public life, such a narrow, egotistic way of
                    contemplating things is of course harmful.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Contemplation of my life
                    Decides the choice
                    Between advance and retreat.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This is the place of transition. We no longer look outward to receive pictures
                    that are more or less limited and confused, but direct out contemplation upon
                    ourselves in order to find a guideline for our decisions. This self-
                    contemplation means the overcoming of naive egotism in the person who
                    sees everything solely form his own standpoint. He begins to reflect and in
                    this way acquires objectivity. However, self-knowledge does not mean
                    preoccupation with one's own thoughts; rather, it means concern about the
                    effects one creates. It is only the effects our lives produce that give us the
                    right to judge whether what we have done means progress or regression.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Contemplation of the light of the kingdom.
                    It furthers one to exert influence as the guest of a king.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This describes a man who understands the secrets by which a kingdom can be
                    made to flourish. Such a man must be given an authoritative position, in
                    which he can exert influence. He should be, so to speak, a guest-that is, he
                    should be honored and act independently, and should not be used as a tool.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Contemplation of his life.
                    The superior man is without blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    While the preceding line represents a man who contemplates himself, here
                    in the highest place everything that is personal, related to the ego, is excluded.
                    The picture is that of a sage who stands outside the affairs of the world.
                    Liberated from his ego, he contemplates the laws of life and so realizes that
                    knowing how to become free of blame is the highest good.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Biting Through" number="21">
        <description>
            This hexagram represents an open mouth (cf. hexagram 27) with an
            obstruction (in the fourth place) between the teeth. As a result the lips cannot
            meet. To bring them together one must bite energetically through the
            obstacle. Since the hexagram is made up of the trigrams for thunder and for
            lightning, it indicates how obstacles are forcibly removed in nature.
            Energetic biting through overcomes the obstacle that prevents joining of the
            lips; the storm with its thunder and lightning overcomes the disturbing
            tension in nature. Recourse to law and penalties overcomes the disturbances
            of harmonious social life caused by criminals and slanderers. The theme of
            this hexagram is a criminal lawsuit, in contradistinction to that of Sung,
            CONFLICT (6), which refers to civil suits.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                BITING THROUGH has success.
                It is favorable to let justice be administered.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                When an obstacle to union arises, energetic biting through brings success.
                This is true in all situations. Whenever unity cannot be established, the
                obstruction is due to a talebearer and traitor who is interfering and blocking
                the way. To prevent permanent injury, vigorous measures must be taken at
                once. Deliberate obstruction of this sort does not vanish of its own accord.
                Judgment and punishment are required to deter or obviate it.
                  However, it is important to proceed in the right way. The hexagram
                combines Li, clarity, and Chên, excitement. Li is yielding, Chên is hard.
                Unqualified hardness and excitement would be too violent in meting out
                punishment; unqualified clarity and gentleness would be too weak. The two
                together create the just measure. It is of moment that the man who makes
                the decisions (represented by the fifth line) is gentle by nature, while he
                commands respect by his conduct in his position.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Thunder and lighting:
                The image of BITING THROUGH.
                Thus the kings of former times made firm the laws
                Through clearly defined penalties.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Penalties are the individual applications of the law. The laws
                specify the penalties. Clarity prevails when mild and severe
                penalties are differentiated, according to the nature of the crimes.
                This is symbolized by the clarity of lighting. The law is strengthened
                by a just application of penalties. This is symbolized by the terror
                of thunder. This clarity and severity have the effect of instilling
                respect; it is not that the penalties are ends in themselves.
                The obstructions in the social life of man increase when there is a
                lack of clarity in the penal codes and slackness in executing them.
                The only to strengthen the law is to make it clear and make penalties
                certain and swift.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    His feet are fastened in the stocks,
                    So that his toes disappear.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a sentence is imposed the first time a man attempts to do wrong, the
                    penalty is a mild one.  Only the toes are put in the stocks.  This prevents him
                    from sinning further and thus he becomes free of blame.  It is a warning to
                    halt in time on the path of evil.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Bites through tender meat,
                    So that his nose disappears.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It is easy to discriminate between right and wrong in this case;
                    it is like biting through tender meat. But one encounters a
                    hardened sinner, and, aroused by anger, one goes a little too
                    far. The disappearance of the nose in the course of the bite
                    signifies that indignation blots out finer sensibility. However,
                    there is no great harm in this, because the penalty as such is
                    just.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Bites on old dried meat
                    And strikes on something poisonous.
                    Slight humiliation.  No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Punishment is to be carried out by someone who lacks the power and
                    authority to do so.  Therefore the culprits do not submit.  The matter at issue
                    is an old one-as symbolized by salted game-and in dealing with it difficulties
                    arise.  This old meat is spoiled: by taking up the problem the punisher arouses
                    poisonous hatred against himself, and n this way is put in a somewhat
                    humiliating position.  But since punishment was required by the time, he
                    remains free of blame.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Bites on dried gristly meat.
                    Receives metal arrows.
                    It furthers one to be mindful of difficulties
                    And to be persevering.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    There are great obstacles to be overcome, powerful opponents are to be
                    punished. Though this is arduous, the effort succeeds. But it is necessary to
                    be hard as metal and straight as an arrow to surmount the difficulties. If one
                    knows these difficulties and remains persevering, he attains good fortune.
                    The difficult task is achieved in the end.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Bites on dried lean meat.
                    Receives yellow gold.
                    Perseveringly aware of danger.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The case to be decided is indeed not easy but perfectly clear.  Since we
                    naturally incline to leniency, we must make every effort to be like yellow
                    gold-that is, as true as gold and as impartial as yellow, the color of the middle
                    [the mean]. It is only by remaining conscious of the dangers growing out of
                    the responsibility we have assumed that we can avoid making mistakes.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    His neck is fastened in the wooden cangue,
                    So that his ears disappear.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In contrast to the first line, this line refers to a man who is incorrigible. His
                    punishment is the wooden cangue, and his ears disappear under it-that is to
                    say, he is deaf to warnings. This obstinacy leads to misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Grace" number="22">
        <description>
            This hexagram shows a fire that breaks out of the secret depths of the earth
            and, blazing up, illuminates and beautifies the mountain, the heavenly
            heights. Grace-beauty of form-is necessary in any union if it is to be well
            ordered and pleasing rather than disordered and chaotic.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                GRACE has success.
                In small matters
                It is favorable to undertake something.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Grace brings success. However, it is not the essential or fundamental thing; it
                is only the ornament and therefore be used sparingly and only in little things.
                In the lower trigram of fire a yielding line comes between two strong lines
                and makes them beautiful, but the strong lines are the essential content and
                the weak line is the beautifying form. In the upper trigram of the mountain,
                the strong line takes the lead, so that here again the strong element must be
                regarded as the decisive factor. In nature we see in the sky the strong light of
                the sun; the life of the world depends on it. But this strong, essential thing is
                changed and given pleasing variety by the moon and the stars. In human
                affairs, aesthetic form comes into being when traditions exist that, strong and
                abiding like mountains, are made pleasing by a lucid beauty. By
                contemplating the forms existing in the heavens we come to understand time
                and its changing demands. Through contemplation of the forms existing in
                human society it becomes possible to shape the world.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Fire at the foot of the mountain:
                The image of GRACE.
                Thus does the superior man proceed
                When clearing up current affairs.
                But he dare not decide controversial issues in this way.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The fire, whose light illuminates the mountain and makes it pleasing, does
                not shine far; in the same way, beautiful form suffices to brighten and to
                throw light upon matters of lesser moment, but important questions cannot
                be decided in this way. They require greater earnestness.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    He lends grace to his toes, leaves the carriage, and walks.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A beginner in subordinate place must take upon himself the labor of
                    advancing. There might be an opportunity of surreptitiously easing the way-
                    symbolized by the carriage-but a self-contained man scorns help gained in a
                    dubious fashion. He thinks it more graceful to go on foot than to drive in a
                    carriage under false pretenses.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Lends grace to the beard on his chin.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The beard is not an independent thing; it moves only with the chin. The
                    image therefore means that form is to be considered only as a result and
                    attribute of content. The beard is a superfluous ornament. To devote care to it
                    for its own sake, without regard for the inner content of which it is an
                    ornament, would bespeak a certain vanity.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Graceful and moist.
                    Constant perseverance brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This represents a very charming life situation. One is under the spell of grace
                    and the mellow mood induced by wine. This grace can adorn, but it can also
                    swamp us. Hence the warning not to sink into convivial indolence but to
                    remain constant in perseverance. Good fortune depends on this.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Grace or simplicity?
                    A white horse comes as if on wings.
                    He is not a robber,
                    He will woo at the right time.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An individual is in a situation in which doubts arise as to which is better-to
                    pursue the grace of external brilliance, or to return to simplicity. The doubt
                    itself implies the answer. Confirmation comes from the outside; it comes like
                    a white winged horse. The white color indicates simplicity. At first it may be
                    disappointing to renounce the comforts that might have been obtained, yet
                    one finds peace of mind in a true relationship with the friend who courts
                    him. The winged horse is the symbol of the thoughts that transcend all limits
                    of space and time.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Grace in the hills and gardens.
                    The roll of silk is meager and small.
                    Humiliation, but in the end good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man withdraws from contact with people of the lowlands, who seek
                    nothing but magnificence and luxury, in to the solitude of the heights. There
                    he finds an individual to look up to, whom he would like to have as a friend.
                    But the gifts he has to offer are poor and few, so that he feels ashamed.
                    However, it is not the material gifts that count, but sincerity of feeling, and so
                    all goes well in the end.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Simple grace. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here at the highest stage of development all ornament is discarded. Form no
                    longer conceals content but brings out its value to the full. Perfect grace
                    consists not in exterior ornamentation of the substance, but in the simple
                    fitness of its form.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Splitting Apart" number="23">
        <description>
            The dark lines are about to mount upward and overthrow the last firm, light
            line by exerting a disintegrating influence on it. The inferior, dark forces
            overcome what is superior and strong, not by direct means, but by
            undermining it gradually and imperceptibly, so that it finally collapses.
              The lines of the hexagram present the image of a house, the top line being
            the roof, and because the roof is being shattered the house collapses. The
            hexagram belongs to the ninth month (October-November). The yin power
            pushes up ever more powerfully and is about to supplant the yang power
            altogether.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                SPLITTING APART. IT does not further one
                To go anywhere.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                This pictures a time when inferior people are pushing forward and are about
                to crowd out the few remaining strong and superior men. Under these
                circumstances, which are due to the time, it is not favorable for the superior
                man to undertake anything.
                  The right behavior in such adverse times is to be deduced from the images
                and their attributes. The lower trigram stands for the earth, whose attributes.
                The lower trigram stands for the earth, whose attributes are docility and
                devotion. The upper trigram stands for the mountain, whose attribute is
                stillness. This suggests that one should submit to the bad time and remain
                quiet. For it is a question not of man's doing but of time conditions, which,
                according to the laws of heaven, show an alternation of increase and decrease,
                fullness and emptiness. It is impossible to counteract these conditions of the
                time. Hence it is not cowardice but wisdom to submit and avoid action.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The mountain rests on the earth:
                The image of SPLITTING APART.
                Thus those above can ensure their position
                Only by giving generously to those below.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The mountain rests on the earth. When it is steep and narrow, lacking a
                broad base, it must topple over. Its position is strong only when it rises out of
                the earth broad and great, not proud and steep. So likewise those who rule
                rest on the broad foundation of the people. They too should be generous and
                benevolent, like the earth that carries all. Then they will make their position
                as secure as a mountain is in its tranquillity.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Six at the beginning means:
                    The leg of the bed is split.
                    Those who persevere are destroyed.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Inferior people are on the rise and stealthily begin their destructive
                    burrowing from below in order to undermine the place where the superior
                    man rests. Those followers of the ruler who remain loyal are destroyed by
                    slander and intrigue. The situation bodes disaster, yet there is nothing to do
                    but wait.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    The bed is split at the edge.
                    Those who persevere are destroyed.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The power of the inferior people is growing. The danger draws close to one's
                    person; already there are clear indication, and rest is disturbed. Moreover, in
                    this dangerous situation one is as yet without help or friendly advances from
                    above or below. Extreme caution is necessary in this isolation. One must
                    adjust to the time and promptly avoid the danger. Stubborn perseverance in
                    maintaining one's standpoint would lead to downfall.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    He splits with them. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An individual finds himself in an evil environment to which he is
                    committed by external ties. But he has an inner relationship with a superior
                    man, and through this he attains the stability to free himself from the way of
                    the inferior people around him. This brings him into opposition to them of
                    course, but that is not wrong.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The bed is split up to the skin.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the disaster affects not only the resting place but even the occupant. No
                    warning or other comment is added. Misfortune has reached its peak: it can
                    no longer be warded off.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    A shoal of fishes. Favor comes through the court ladies.
                    Everything acts to further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here, in immediate proximity to the strong, light-giving principle at the top,
                    the nature of the dark force undergoes a change. It no longer opposes the
                    strong principle by means of intrigues but submits to its guidance. Indeed, as
                    the head of the other weak lines, it leads all of these to the strong line, just as
                    a princess leads her maids-in-waiting like a shoal of fishes to her husband and
                    thus gains his favor. Inasmuch as the lower element thus voluntarily places
                    itself under the higher, it attains happiness and the higher also receives its
                    due. Therefore all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    There is a large fruit still uneaten.
                    The superior man receives a carriage.
                    The house of the inferior man is split apart.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the splitting apart reaches its end. When misfortune has spent itself,
                    better times return. The seed of the good remains, and it is just when the
                    fruit falls to the ground that food sprouts anew from its seed. The superior
                    man again attains influence and effectiveness. He is supported by public
                    opinion as if in a carriage. But the inferior man's wickedness is visited upon
                    himself. His house is split apart. A law of nature is at work here. Evil is not
                    destructive to the good alone but inevitably destroys itself as well. For evil,
                    which lives solely by negation, cannot continue to exist on its own strength
                    alone. The inferior man himself fares best when held under control by a
                    superior man.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Return (The Turning Point)" number="24">
        <description>
            The idea of a turning point arises from the fact that after the dark lines have
            pushed all of the light lines upward and out of the hexagram, another light
            line enters the hexagram from below. The time of darkness is past. The
            winter solstice brings the victory of light. This hexagram is linked with the
            eleventh month, the month of the solstice (December-January).
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                RETURN. Success.
                Going out and coming in without error.
                Friends come without blame.
                To and fro goes the way.
                On the seventh day comes return.
                It furthers one to have somewhere to go.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                After a time of decay comes the turning point. The powerful light that has
                been banished returns. There is movement, but it is not brought about by
                force. The upper trigram K'un is characterized by devotion; thus the
                movement is natural, arising spontaneously. For this reason the
                transformation of the old becomes easy. The old is discarded and the new is
                introduced. Both measures accord with the time; therefore no harm results.
                Societies of people sharing the same views are formed. But since these
                groups come together in full public knowledge and are in harmony with the
                time, all selfish separatist tendencies are excluded, and no mistake is made.
                The idea of RETURN is based on the course of nature. The movement is
                cyclic, and the course completes itself. Therefore it is not necessary to hasten
                anything artificially. Everything comes of itself at the appointed time. This is
                the meaning of heaven and earth.
                  All movements are accomplished in six stages, and the seventh brings
                return. Thus the winter solstice, with which the decline of the year begins,
                comes in the seventh month after the summer solstice; so too sunrise comes
                in the seventh double hour after sunset. Therefore seven is the number of
                the young light, and it arises when six, the number of the great darkness, is
                increased by one. In this way the state of rest gives place to movement.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Thunder within the earth:
                The image of THE TURNING POINT.
                Thus the kings of antiquity closed the passes
                At the time of solstice.
                Merchants and strangers did not go about,
                And the ruler
                Did not travel through the provinces.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The winter solstice has always been celebrated in China as the resting time of
                the year— a custom that survives in the time of rest observed at the new year.
                In winter the life energy, symbolized by thunder, the Arousing, is still
                underground. Movement is just at its beginning; therefore it must be
                strengthened by rest so that it will not be dissipated by being used
                prematurely. This principle, i.e., of allowing energy that is renewing itself to
                be reinforced by rest, applies to all similar situations. The return of health
                after illness, the return of understanding after an estrangement: everything
                must be treated tenderly and with care at the beginning, so that the return
                may lead to a flowering.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Return from a short distance.
                    No need for remorse.
                    Great good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Slight digressions from the good cannot be avoided, but one must turn back
                    in time, before going too far. This is especially important in the development
                    of character; every faintly evil thought must be put aside immediately, before
                    it goes too far and takes root in the mind. Then there is no cause for remorse,
                    and all goes well.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Quiet return. Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Return always calls for a decision and is an act of self-mastery. It is made
                    easier if a man is in good company. If he can bring himself to put aside pride
                    and follow the example of good men, good fortune results.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Repeated return. Danger. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    There are people of a certain inner instability who feel a constant urge to
                    reverse themselves. There is danger in continually deserting the good
                    because of uncontrolled desires, then turning back to it again because of a
                    better resolution. However, since this does not lead to habituation in evil, a
                    general inclination to overcome the defect is not wholly excluded.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Walking in the midst of others,
                    One returns alone.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man is in a society composed of inferior people, but is connected spiritually
                    with a strong and good friend, and this makes him turn back alone.
                    Although nothing is said of reward and punishment, this return is certainly
                    favorable, for such a resolve to choose the good brings its own reward.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Noblehearted return. No remorse.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When the time for return has come, a man should not take shelter in trivial
                    excuses, but should look within and examine himself. And if he has done
                    something wrong he should make a noblehearted resolve to confess his fault.
                    No one will regret having taken this road.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Missing the return. Misfortune.
                    Misfortune from within and without.
                    If armies are set marching in this way,
                    One will in the end suffer a great defeat,
                    Disastrous for the ruler of the country.
                    For ten years
                    It will not be possible to attack again.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    If a man misses the right time for return, he meets with misfortune. The
                    misfortune has its inner cause in a wrong attitude toward the world. The
                    misfortune coming upon him for without results from this wrong attitude.
                    What is pictured here is blind obstinacy and the judgment that is visited
                    upon it.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Innocence (The Unexpected)" number="25">
        <description>
            Ch'ien, heaven is above; Chên, movement, is below. The lower trigram
            Chên is under the influence of the strong line it has received form above,
            from heaven. When, in accord with this, movement follows the law of
            heaven, man is innocent and without guile. His mind is natural and true,
            unshadowed by reflection or ulterior designs. For wherever conscious
            purpose is to be seen, there the truth and innocence of nature have been lost.
            Nature that is not directed by the spirit is not true but degenerate nature.
            Starting out with the idea of the natural, the train of thought in part goes
            somewhat further and thus the hexagram includes also the idea of the
            fundamental or unexpected.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                INNOCENCE. Supreme success.
                Perseverance furthers.
                If someone is not as he should be,
                He has misfortune,
                And it does not further him
                To undertake anything.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Man has received from heaven a nature innately good, to guide him in all his
                movements. By devotion to this divine spirit within himself, he attains an
                unsullied innocence that leads him to do right with instinctive sureness and
                without any ulterior thought of reward and personal advantage. This
                instinctive certainty brings about supreme success and 'furthers through
                perseverance". However, not everything instinctive is nature in this higher
                sense of the word, but only that which is right and in accord with the will of
                heaven. Without this quality of rightness, an unreflecting, instinctive way of
                acting brings only misfortune. Confucius says about this: "He who departs
                from innocence, what does he come to? Heaven's will and blessing do not go
                with his deeds."
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Under heaven thunder rolls:
                All things attain the natural state of innocence.
                Thus the kings of old,
                Rich in virtue, and in harmony with the time,
                Fostered and nourished all beings.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In springtime when thunder, life energy, begins to move again under the
                heavens, everything sprouts and grows, and all beings receive for the creative
                activity of nature the childlike innocence of their original state. So it is with
                the good rulers of mankind: drawing on the spiritual wealth at their
                command, they take care of all forms of life and all forms of culture and do
                everything to further them, and at the proper time.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Innocent behavior brings good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The original impulses of the heart are always good, so that we may follow
                    them confidently, assured of good fortune and achievement of our aims.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    If one does not count on the harvest while plowing,
                    Nor on the use of the ground while clearing it,
                    It furthers one to undertake something.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We should do every task for its own sake as time and place demand and not
                    with an eye to the result. Then each task turns out well, and anything we
                    undertake succeeds.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Undeserved misfortune.
                    The cow that was tethered by someone
                    Is the wanderer's gain, the citizen's loss.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Sometimes undeserved misfortune befalls a man at the hands of another, as
                    for instance when someone passes by and takes a tethered cow along with
                    him. His gain is the owner's loss. In all transactions, no matter how
                    innocent, we must accommodate ourselves to the demands of the time,
                    otherwise unexpected misfortune overtakes us.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    He who can be persevering
                    Remains without blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    We cannot lose what really belongs to us, even if we throw it away.
                    Therefore we need have no anxiety. All that need concern us is that we
                    should remain true to our own natures and not listen to others.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Use no medicine in an illness
                    Incurred through no fault of your own.
                    It will pass of itself.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    An unexpected evil may come accidentally from without. If it does not
                    originate in one's own nature or have a foothold there, one should not resort
                    to external means to eradicate it, but should quietly let nature take its course.
                    Then improvement will come of itself.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Innocent action brings misfortune.
                    Nothing furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When, in a given situation, the time is not ripe for further progress, the best
                    thing to do is to wait quietly, without ulterior designs. If one acts
                    thoughtlessly and tries to push ahead in opposition to fate, success will not be
                    achieved.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Taming Power of the Great" number="26">
        <description>
            The Creative is tamed by Kên, Keeping Still.  This produces great power, a
            situation in contrast to that of the ninth hexagram, Hsiao Ch'u, THE
            TAMING POWER OF THE SMALL, in which the Creative is tamed by the
            Gentle alone. There one weak line must tame five strong lines, but here four
            strong lines are restrained by two weak lines; in addition to a minister, there
            is a prince, and the restraining power therefore is afar stronger.
              The hexagram has a threefold meaning, expressing different aspects of the
            concept "Holding firm." Heaven within the mountain gives the idea of
            holding firm in the sense of holding together; the trigram Kên which holds
            the trigram ch'ien still, gives the idea of holding firm in the sense of holding
            back; the third idea is that of holding firm in the sense of caring for and
            nourishing. This last is suggested by the fact that a strong line at the top,
            which is the ruler of the hexagram, is honored and tended as a sage. The third
            of these meanings also attaches specifically to this strong line at the top,
            which represents the sage.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE TAMING POWER OF THE GREAT.
                Perseverance furthers.
                Not eating at home brings good fortune.
                It furthers one to cross the great water.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                To hold firmly to great creative powers and store them up, as set forth in this
                hexagram, there is need of a strong, clear-headed man who is honored by the
                ruler. The trigram Ch'ein points to strong creative power; Kên indicates
                firmness and truth. Both point to light and clarity and to the daily renewal of
                character. Only through such daily self-renewal can a man continue at the
                height of his powers. Force of habit helps to keep order in quiet times; but in
                periods when there is a great storing up of energy, everything depends on the
                power of the personality. However, since the worthy are honored, as in the
                case of the strong personality entrusted with leadership by the ruler, it is an
                advantage not to eat at home but rather to earn one's bread by entering upon
                public office. Such a man is in harmony with heaven; therefore even great
                and difficult undertakings, such as crossing the great water, succeed.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Heaven within the mountain:
                The image of THE TAMING POWER OF THE GREAT.
                Thus the superior man acquaints himself with many sayings of antiquity
                And many deeds of the past,
                In order to strengthen his character thereby.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Heaven within the mountain points to hidden treasures. In the words and
                deeds of the past there lies hidden a treasure that men may use to strengthen
                and elevate their own characters. The way to study the past is not to confine
                oneself to mere knowledge of history but, through application of this
                knowledge, to give actuality to the past.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Danger is at hand. It furthers one to desist.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man wishes to make vigorous advance, but circumstances present an
                    obstacle. He sees himself held back firmly. If he should attempt to fore an
                    advance, it would lead him into misfortune. Therefore it is better for him to
                    compose himself and to wait until an outlet is offered for release of his
                    stored-up energies.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    The axletrees are taken from the wagon.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here advance is checked just as in the third line of THE TAMING POWER OF
                    THE SMALL (9). However, in the later the restraining force is slight; thus a
                    conflict arises between the propulsive and the restraining movement, as a
                    result of which the spokes fall out of the wagon wheels, while here the
                    restraining force is absolutely superior; hence no struggle takes place. One
                    submits and removes the axletrees from the wagon -in other words, contents
                    himself with waiting. In this way energy accumulates for a vigorous advance
                    later on.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    A good horse that follows others.
                    Awareness of danger,
                    With perseverance, furthers.
                    Practice chariot driving and armed defense daily.
                    It furthers one to have somewhere to go.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The way opens; the hindrance has been cleared away. A man is in contact
                    with a strong will acting in the same direction as his own, and goes forward
                    like one good horse following another. But danger still threatens, and he
                    must remain aware of it, or he will be robbed of his firmness. Thus he must
                    acquire skill on the one hand in what will take him forward, and on the other
                    in what will protect him against unforeseen attacks. It is good in such a pass
                    to have a goal toward which to strive.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The headboard of a young bull.
                    Great good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This line and the one following it are the two that tame the forward-pushing
                    lower lines. Before a bull's horns grow out, a headboard is fastened to its
                    forehead, so that later when the horns appear they cannot do harm. A good
                    way to restrain wild force is to forestall it. By so doing one achieves an easy
                    and great success.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    The tusk of a gelded boar.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the restraining of the impetuous forward drive is achieved in an
                    indirect way. A boar's tusk is in itself dangerous, but if the boar's nature is
                    altered, the tusk is no longer a menace. Thus also where men are concerned,
                    wild force should not be combated directly; instead, its roots should be eradicated.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    One attains the way of heaven.
                    Success.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The time of obstruction is past. The energy long dammed up by inhibition
                    forces its way out and achieves great success. This refers to a man who is
                    honored by the ruler and whose principles now prevail and shape the world.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Corners of the Mouth (Providing Nourishment)" number="1">
        <description>
            This hexagram is a picture of an open mouth; above and below are firm lines
            of the lips, and between them the opening. Starting with the mouth, through
            which we take food for nourishment, the thought leads to nourishment
            itself. Nourishment of oneself, specifically of the body, is represented in the
            three lower lines, while the three upper lines represent nourishment and
            care of others, in a higher, spiritual sense.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE CORNERS OF THE MOUTH.
                Perseverance brings good fortune.
                Pay heed to the providing of nourishment
                And to what a man seeks
                To fill his own mouth with.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                In bestowing care and nourishment, it is important that the right people
                should be taken care of and that we should attend to our own nourishment
                in the right way. If we wish to know what anyone is like, we have only to
                observe on whom he bestows his care and what sides of his own nature he
                cultivates and nourishes. Nature nourishes all creatures. The great man
                fosters and takes care of superior men, in order to take care of all men
                through them. Mencius says about this:

                If we wish to know whether anyone is superior or not, we need only observe
                what part of his being he regards as especially important. The body has
                superior and inferior, important and unimportant parts. We must not injure
                important parts for the sake of the unimportant, nor must we injure the
                superior parts for the sake of the inferior. He who cultivates the inferior parts
                of his nature is an inferior man. He who cultivates the superior parts of his
                nature is a superior man.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                At the foot of the mountain, thunder:
                The image of PROVIDING NOURISHMENT.
                Thus the superior man is careful of his words
                And temperate in eating and drinking.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                "God comes forth in the sign of the Arousing": when in the spring the life
                forces stir again, all things comes into being anew. "He brings to perfection in
                the sign of Keeping Still": thus in the early spring, when the seeds fall to
                earth, all things are made ready. This is an image of providing nourishment
                through movement and tranquillity.  The superior man takes it as a pattern
                for the nourishment and cultivation of his character. Words are a movement
                going form within outward. Eating and drinking are movements from
                without inward. Both kinds of movement can be modified by tranquillity.
                For tranquillity keeps the words that come out of the mouth from exceeding
                proper measure, and keeps the food that goes into the mouth from exceeding
                its proper measure. Thus character is cultivated.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    You let your magic tortoise go,
                    And look at me with the corners of your mouth drooping.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    The magic tortoise is a creature possessed of such supernatural powers that it
                    lives on air and needs no earthly nourishment. The image means that a man
                    fitted by nature and position to live freely and independently renounces this
                    self-reliance and instead looks with envy and discontent at others who are
                    outwardly in better circumstances. But such base envy only arouses derision
                    and contempt in those others. This has bad results.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Turning to the summit for nourishment,
                    Deviating from the path
                    To seek nourishment from the hill.
                    Continuing to do this brings misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Normally a person either provides his own means of nourishment or is
                    supported in a proper way by those whose duty of privilege it is to provide for
                    him. If, owing to weakness of spirit, a man cannot support himself, a feeling
                    of uneasiness comes over him; this is because in shirking the proper way of
                    obtaining a living, he accepts support as a favor from those in higher place.
                    This is unworthy, for he is deviating from his true nature. Kept up
                    indefinitely, this course leads to misfortune.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Turning away from nourishment.
                    Perseverance brings misfortune.
                    Do not act thus for ten years.
                    Nothing serves to further.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    He who seeks nourishment that does not nourish reels from desire to
                    gratification and in gratification craves desire. Mad pursuit of pleasure for the
                    satisfaction of the senses never brings one to the goal. One should never (ten
                    years is a complete cycle of time) follow this path, for nothing good can come
                    of it.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Turning to the summit
                    For provision of nourishment
                    Brings good fortune.
                    Spying about with sharp eyes
                    Like a tiger with insatiable craving.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In contrast to the six in the second place, which refers to a man bent
                    exclusively on his own advantage, this line refers to one occupying a high
                    position and striving to let his light sine forth. To do this he needs helpers,
                    because he cannot attain his lofty aim alone. With the greed of a hungry tiger
                    he is on the lookout for the right people. Since he is not working for himself
                    but for the good of all, there is no wrong in such zeal.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Turning away from the path.
                    To remain persevering brings good fortune.
                    One should not cross the great water.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man may be conscious of a deficiency in himself. He should be
                    undertaking the nourishment of the people, but he has not the strength to do
                    it. Thus he must turn from his accustomed path and beg counsel and help
                    from a man who is spiritually his superior but undistinguished outwardly. If
                    he maintains this attitude of mind perseveringly, success and good fortune
                    are his. But he must remain aware of his dependence. He must not put his
                    own person forward nor attempt great labors, such as crossing the great water.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The source of nourishment.
                    Awareness of danger brings good fortune.
                    It furthers one to cross the great water.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This describes a sage of the highest order, from whom emanate all influences
                    that provide nourishment for others. Such a position brings with it heavy
                    responsibility. If he remains conscious of this fact, he has good fortune and
                    may confidently undertake even great and difficult labors, such as crossing
                    the great water. These undertakings bring general happiness for him and for
                    all others.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="Preponderance of the Great" number="28">
        <description>
            This hexagram consists of four strong lines inside and two weak lines outside.
            When the strong are outside and the weak inside, all is well and there is
            nothing out of balance, nothing extraordinary in the situation. Here,
            however, the opposite is the case. The hexagram represents a beam that is
            thick and heavy in the middle but too weak at the ends. This is a condition
            that cannot last; it must be changed, must pass, or misfortune will result.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                PREPONDERANCE OF THE GREAT.
                The ridgepole sags to the breaking point.
                It furthers one to have somewhere to go.
                Success.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                The weight of the great is excessive. The load is too heavy for the strength of
                the supports. The ridgepole on which the whole roof rests, sags to the
                breaking point, because its supporting ends are too weak for the load they
                bear. It is an exceptional time and situation; therefore extraordinary measures
                are demanded. It is necessary to find a way of transition as quickly as possible,
                and to take action. This promises success. For although the strong element is
                in excess, it is in the middle, that is, at the center of gravity, so that a
                revolution is not to be feared. Nothing is to be achieved by forcible measures.
                The problem must be solved by gently penetration to the meaning of the
                situation (as is suggested by the attribute of the inner trigram, Sun); then the
                change-over to other conditions will be successful. It demands real
                superiority; therefore the time when the great preponderates is a momentous
                time.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                The lake rises above the trees:
                The image of PREPONDERANCE OF THE GREAT.
                Thus the superior man, when he stands alone,
                Is unconcerned,
                And if he has to renounce the world,
                He is undaunted.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Extraordinary times when the great preponderates are like flood times when
                the lake rises over the treetops. But such conditions are temporary. The two
                trigrams indicate the attitude proper to such exceptional times: the symbol of
                the trigram Sun is the tree, which stands firm even though it stands alone,
                and the attribute of Tui is joyousness, which remains undaunted even if it
                must renounce the world.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Six at the beginning means:
                    To spread white rushes underneath.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When a man wishes to undertake an enterprise in extraordinary times, he
                    must be extraordinarily cautious, just as when setting a heavy thing down on
                    the floor, one takes care to put rushes under it, so that nothing will break.
                    This caution, though it may seem exaggerated, is not a mistake. Exceptional
                    enterprises cannot succeed unless utmost caution is observed in their
                    beginnings and in the laying of their foundations.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    A dry poplar sprouts at the root.
                    An older man takes a young wife.
                    Everything furthers.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Wood is near water; hence the image of an old poplar sprouting at the root.
                    This means an extraordinary situation arises when an older man marries a
                    young girl who suits him. Despite the unusualness of the situation, all goes
                    well.
                      From the point of view of politics, the meaning is that in exceptional times
                    one does well to join with the lowly, for this affords a possibility of renewal.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    The ridgepole sags to the breaking point.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    This indicates a type of man who in times of preponderance of the great
                    insists on pushing ahead. He accepts no advice from others, and therefore
                    they in turn are not willing to lend him support. Because of this the burden
                    grows, until the structure of things bends or breaks. Plunging willfully ahead
                    in times of danger only hastens the catastrophe.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    The ridgepole is braced. Good fortune.
                    If there are ulterior motives, it is humiliating.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Through friendly relations with people of lower rank, a responsible man
                    succeeds in becoming master of the situation. But if, instead of working for
                    the rescue of the whole, he were to misuse his connections to obtain personal
                    power and success, it would lead to humiliation.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    A withered poplar puts forth flowers.
                    An older woman takes a husband.
                    No blame. No praise.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A withered poplar that flowers exhausts its energies thereby and only hastens
                    its end. An older woman may marry once more, but no renewal takes place.
                    Everything remains barren. Thus, though all the amenities are observed, the
                    net result is only the anomaly of the situation.
                      Applied to politics, the metaphor means that if in times of insecurity we
                    give up alliance with those below us and keep up only the relationships we
                    have with people of higher rank, an unstable situation is created.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    One must go through the water.
                    It goes over one's head.
                    Misfortune. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here is a situation in which the unusual has reached a climax. One is
                    courageous and wishes to accomplish one's task, no matter what happens.
                    This leads into danger. The water rises over one's head. This is the
                    misfortune. But one incurs no blame in giving up one's life that the good
                    and the right may prevail. There are things that are more important than
                    life.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Abysmal (Water)" number="29">
        <description>
            This hexagram consists of a doubling of the trigram K'an. It is one of the
            eight hexagrams in which doubling occurs. The trigram K'an means a
            plunging in. A yang line has plunged in between two yin lines and is closed
            in by them like water in a ravine. The trigram K'an is also the middle son.
            The Receptive has obtained the middle line of the Creative, and thus K'an
            develops. As an image it represents water, the water that comes from above
            and is in motion on earth in streams and rivers, giving rise to all life on
            earth.
              In man's world K'an represents the heart, the soul locked up within the
            body, the principle of light inclosed in the dark— that is, reason. The name of
            the hexagram, because the trigram is doubled, has the additional meaning,
            "repetition of danger." Thus the hexagram is intended to designate an
            objective situation to which one must become accustomed, not a subjective
            attitude. For danger due to a subjective attitude means either foolhardiness
            or guile. Hence too a ravine is used to symbolize danger; it is a situation in
            which a man is in the same pass as the water in a ravine, and, like the water,
            he can escape if he behaves correctly.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                The Abysmal repeated.
                If you are sincere, you have success in your heart,
                And whatever you do succeeds.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Through repetition of danger we grow accustomed to it. Water sets the
                example for the right conduct under such circumstances. It flows on and on,
                and merely fills up all the places through which it flows; it does not shrink
                from any dangerous spot nor from any plunge, and nothing can make it lose
                its own essential nature. It remains true to itself under all conditions. Thus
                likewise, if one is sincere when confronted with difficulties, the heart can
                penetrate the meaning of the situation. And once we have gained inner
                mastery of a problem, it will come about naturally that the action we take will
                succeed. In danger all that counts is really carrying out all that has to be done-
                -thoroughness— and going forward, in order not to perish through tarrying in
                the danger.
                  Properly used, danger can have an important meaning as a protective
                measure. Thus heaven has its perilous height protecting it against every
                attempt at invasion, and earth has its mountains and bodies of water,
                separating countries by their dangers. Thus also rulers make use of danger to
                protect themselves against attacks from without and against turmoil within.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                Water flows on uninterruptedly and reaches its foal:
                The image of the Abysmal repeated.
                Thus the superior man walks in lasting virtue
                And carries on the business of teaching.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Water reaches its goal by flowing continually. It fills up every depression
                before it flows on. The superior man follows its example; he is concerned
                that goodness should be an established attribute of character rather than an
                accidental and isolated occurrence. So likewise in teaching others everything
                depends on consistency, for it is only through repetition that the pupil makes
                the material his own.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    Repetition of the Abysmal.
                    In the abyss one falls into a pit.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    By growing used to what is dangerous, a man can easily allow it to become
                    part of him. He is familiar with it and grows used to evil. With this he has
                    lost the right way, and misfortune is the natural result.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    The abyss is dangerous.
                    One should strive to attain small things only.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    When we are in danger we ought not to attempt to get out of it immediately,
                    regardless of circumstances; at first we must content ourselves with not being
                    overcome by it. We must calmly weigh the conditions of the time and by
                    satisfied with small gains, because for the time being a great success cannot be
                    attained. A spring flows only sparingly at first, and tarries for some time
                    before it makes its way in to the open.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    Forward and backward, abyss on abyss.
                    In danger like this, pause at first and wait,
                    Otherwise you will fall into a pit in the abyss.
                    Do not act this way.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here every step, forward or backward, leads into danger. Escape is out of the
                    question. Therefore we must not be misled into action, as a result of which
                    we should only bog down deeper in the danger; disagreeable as it may be to
                    remain in such a situation, we must wait until a way out shows itself.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    A jug of wine, a bowl of rice with it;
                    Earthen vessels
                    Simply handed in through the Window.
                    There is certainly no blame in this.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    In times of danger ceremonious forms are dropped. What matters most is
                    sincerity. Although as a rule it is customary for an official to present certain
                    introductory gifts and recommendations before he is appointed, here
                    everything is simplified to the utmost. The gifts are insignificant, there is no
                    one to sponsor him, he introduces himself; yet all this need not be
                    humiliating if only there is the honest intention of mutual help in danger.
                    Still another idea is suggested. The window is the place through which light
                    enters the room. If in difficult times we want to enlighten someone, we must
                    begin with that which is in itself lucid and proceed quite simply from that
                    point on.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    The abyss is not filled to overflowing,
                    It is filled only to the rim.
                    No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Danger comes because one is too ambitious. In order to flow out of a ravine,
                    water does not rise higher than the lowest point of the rim. So likewise a
                    man when in danger has only to proceed along the line of least resistance;
                    thus he reaches the goal. Great labors cannot be accomplished in such times; it
                    is enough to get out of the danger.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    Bound with cords and ropes,
                    Shut in between thorn-hedged prison walls:
                    For three years one does not find the way.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    A man who in the extremity of danger has lost the right way and is
                    irremediably entangled in his sins has no prospect of escape. He is like a
                    criminal who sits shackled behind thorn hedged prison walls.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Clinging, Fire" number="29">
        <description>
            This hexagram is another double sign. The trigram Li means "to cling to
            something," and also "brightness." A dark line clings to two light lines, one
            above and one below— the image of an empty space between two strong lines,
            whereby the two strong lines are made bright. The trigram represents the
            middle daughter. The Creative has incorporated the central line of the
            Receptive, and thus Li develops. As an image, it is fire. Fire has no definite
            form but clings to the burning object and thus is bright. As water pours down
            from heaven, so fire flames up from the earth. While K'an means the soul
            shut within the body, Li stands for nature in its radiance.
        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                THE CLINGING. Perseverance furthers.
                It brings success.
                Care of the cow brings good fortune.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                What is dark clings to what is light and so enhances the brightness of the
                latter. A luminous thing giving out light must have within itself something
                that perseveres; otherwise it will in time burn itself out. Everything that gives
                light is dependent on something to which it clings, in order that it may
                continue to shine.
                  Thus the sun and moon cling to heaven, and grain, grass, and trees cling to
                the earth. So too the twofold clarity of the dedicated man clings to what is
                right and thereby can shape the world. Human life on earth is conditioned
                and unfree, and when man recognizes this limitation and makes himself
                dependent upon the harmonious and beneficent forces of the cosmos, he
                achieves success. The cow is the symbol of extreme docility. By cultivating in
                himself an attitude of compliance and voluntary dependence, man acquires
                clarity without sharpness and finds his place in the world.
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                That which is bright rises twice:
                The image of FIRE.
                Thus the great man, by perpetuating this brightness,
                Illumines the four quarters of the world.
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                Each of the two trigrams represents the sun in the course of a day. The two
                together represent the repeated movement of the sun, the function of light
                with respect to time. The great man continues the work of nature in the
                human world. Through the clarity of his nature he causes the light to spread
                farther and farther and to penetrate the nature of man ever more deeply.
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    The footprints run crisscross.
                    If one is seriously intent, no blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It is early morning and work begins. The mind has been closed to the outside
                    world in sleep; now its connections with the world begin again. The traces of
                    one's impressions run crisscross. Activity and haste prevail. It is important
                    then to preserve inner composure and not to allow oneself to be swept along
                    by the bustle of life. If one is serious and composed, he can acquire the clarity
                    of mind needed for coming to terms with the innumerable impressions that
                    pour in. It is precisely at the beginning that serious concentration is
                    important, because the beginning holds the seed of all that is to follow.
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>
                    Yellow light. Supreme good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Midday has come; the sun shines with a yellow light. Yellow is the color of
                    measure and mean. Yellow light is therefore a symbol of the highest culture
                    and art, whose consummate harmony consists in holding to the mean.
                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>
                    In the light of the setting sun,
                    Men either beat the pot and sing
                    Or loudly bewail the approach of old age.
                    Misfortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the end of the day has come. The light of the setting sun calls to mind
                    the fact that life is transitory and conditional. Caught in this external
                    bondage, men are usually robbed of their inner freedom as well. The sense of
                    the transitoriness of life impels them to uninhibited revelry in order to enjoy
                    life while it lasts, or else they yield to melancholy and spoil the precious time
                    by lamenting the approach of old age. Both attitudes are wrong. To the
                    superior man it makes no difference whether death comes early or late. He
                    cultivates himself, awaits his allotted time, and in this way secures his fate.
                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>
                    Its coming is sudden;
                    It flames up, dies down, is thrown away.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Clarity of mind has the same relation to life that fire has to wood. Fire clings
                    to wood, but also consumes it. Clarity of mind is rooted in life but can also
                    consume it. Everything depends upon how the clarity functions. Here the
                    image used is that of a meteor or a straw fire. A man who is excitable and
                    restless may rise quickly to prominence but produces no lasting effects. Thus
                    matters end badly when a man spends himself too rapidly and consumes
                    himself like a meteor.
                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>
                    Tears in floods, sighing and lamenting.
                    Good fortune.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    Here the zenith of life has been reached. Were there no warning, one would
                    at this point consume oneself like a flame. Instead, understanding the vanity
                    of all things, one may put aside both hope and fear, and sigh and lament: if
                    one is intent on retaining his clarity of mind, good fortune will come from
                    this grief. For here we are dealing not with a passing mood, as in the nine in
                    the third place, but with a real change of heart.
                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>
                    The king used him to march forth and chastise.
                    Then it is best to kill the leaders
                    And take captive the followers. No blame.
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    It is not the purpose of chastisement to impose punishment blindly but to
                    create discipline. Evil must be cured at its roots. To eradicate evil in political
                    life, it is best to kill the ringleaders and spare the followers. In educating
                    oneself it is best to root out bad habits and tolerate those that are harmless.
                    For asceticism that is too strict, like sentences of undue severity, fails in its
                    purpose.
                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description>

        </description>
        <judgement>
            <text>

            </text>
            <interpretation>

            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>

    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
    <hexagram name="The Creative" number="1">
        <description></description>
        <judgement>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </judgement>
        <image>
            <text>
                
            </text>
            <interpretation>
                
            </interpretation>
        </image>
        <lines>
            <one>
                <text>
                    
                </text>
                <meaning>
                    
                </meaning>
            </one>
            <two>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </two>
            <three>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </three>
            <four>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </four>
            <five>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </five>
            <six>
                <text>

                </text>
                <meaning>

                </meaning>
            </six>
        </lines>
    </hexagram>
</hexagrams>